Wave
波
technology
テクノロジー
Message
メッセージ
General Zhu is a very important political scientist
朱将軍は非常に重要な政治学者です
Professor Wu Yushan, I don't think I need a special introduction
呉玉山教授、特別な紹介は必要ないと思います
You can sometimes see him in the newspapers
時々新聞で彼を見かけます
Comments on ten moves
10手についてのコメント
But I still want to briefly introduce his resume
それでも彼の履歴書を簡単に紹介したいと思います
Dr Wu is a 1976 graduate of Jianguo Middle School
ウー博士は建国中学校を 1976 年に卒業しました。
I think many of you recall the time in 1970
1970年当時を覚えている方も多いと思います
The international situation in Taiwan at that time
当時の台湾の国際情勢
When official changes are dramatic
公式な変更が劇的な場合
The international situation was already very unfavorable to the Republic of China at that time
当時、国際情勢はすでに中華民国にとって非常に不利でした。
So at that time, Dr. Wu was admitted to the Political Science Department of National Taiwan University for the first time.
そのとき、呉博士は国立台湾大学政治学部に初めて入学した。
Hope to make a difference to reality
現実に変化をもたらすことを願っています
Four years later he graduated first
4年後、彼は一番最初に卒業した
In fact, he graduated first in all of them.
実際、彼はそのすべてで首席で卒業しました。
He graduated first from all of this
彼はこれらすべてを一番最初に卒業した
Then what
じゃあ何
In order to understand the other side and international communism, I am admitted to politics
相手の側と国際共産主義を理解するために政治家になる
Also graduated first in 1980
こちらも1980年に首席卒業
Applying for entry after two years of benefits
2年間の給付金受給後の入国申請
Department of Political Science, University of California, Berkeley
カリフォルニア大学バークレー校政治学部
Then his question was
そこで彼の質問はこうだった
Nominalist State and Property Rights
唯名論的な国家と財産権
Mutual Ping is the Study of Economic Reform in Mainland China
相互ピンは中国本土の経済改革の研究です
Also received in 1992
1992年にも受賞
American Political Science Association's Best Ph.D. Player
アメリカ政治学協会の最優秀博士号選手
After he came back, he worked in the Department of Political Science, National Taiwan University.
帰国後は国立台湾大学政治学部に勤務。
Director of Intervention Affairs from Associate Professor
准教授より介入担当部長
Then in 2006 to Zhongyuan Institute
その後、2006 年に中原研究所へ
director of political science empowerment
政治学エンパワーメント担当ディレクター
Currently a designated salesperson and director
現在、指定販売者兼取締役
Dr. Lin got a lot of lives
リン博士はたくさんの命をもらいました
He has won national science awards three times
彼は国家科学賞を3回受賞しています
National Taiwan University Mobile Teaching Award
国立台湾大学モバイルティーチング賞
Ministry of Education Academic Award
文部科学大臣学術賞
Twice National Academy of Sciences Award
米国科学アカデミー賞を2回受賞
And outstanding specific rescuers
そして優秀な特定救助者
And he also served as a member of the National Science and Technology Department
そして、彼は国家科学技術局のメンバーも務めました。
Top Ph.D. players named in political science
政治学分野で博士号取得のトップ選手が選出される
Is the shaper of political science
政治学の形成者である
His field of study includes the Socialist State
彼の研究分野には社会主義国家が含まれます
Political and Economic Transformation Democratization and Constitutional Design
政治的・経済的変革 民主化と憲法設計
Cross-strait relations and international theory
両岸関係と国際理論
And lead Taiwan's semi-funded research
台湾の半資金提供による研究を主導
Theoreticalization of research on cross-strait relations
両岸関係研究の理論化
Fifteen books in English written and edited by him
彼が執筆、編集した英語の本 15 冊
Books in Chinese and English More than 100 journals and book papers
中国語と英語の書籍 100 以上の雑誌と書籍論文
Here I should introduce Director Wu
ここでウー監督を紹介したいと思います
Director Wu does not need to read the documents
呉所長は文書を読む必要はありません
Because I know all too well about his whole academics and science too
なぜなら、私は彼の学問や科学についてもよく知っているからです。
and adore
そして崇拝します
When I was in Guoke local culture modeling people
私がGuokeで地元の文化のモデルをしていたとき
I happen to be the director of the humanities department
私はたまたま人文科学部の部長です
So I have a lot of work with him
だから私は彼と一緒にたくさんの仕事をしている
There are also academic professors
学術的な教授もいます
I also admire his research very much.
私も彼の研究をとても尊敬しています。
The topic he is going to talk about today
彼が今日話そうとしている話題
I was eating just now
ちょうど今食べてたところだった
Exchange your relics with Director Wu
ウー長官と遺物を交換する
I think it's an interesting topic
興味深い話題だと思います
And it's good for impromptu
そしてそれは即興にも適しています
i don't know how you guys are doing
皆さんはどうしているか分かりません
I always think inside
私はいつも心の中で考えています
Wow, political development should be like this today
うわー、今日の政治発展はこうあるべきだ
It's almost there. The next game hasn't progressed yet.
もうすぐだ、まだ次のゲームは進んでいない。
10 years later
10年後
Politics still has a new round
政治はまだ新たなラウンドを迎えている
will affect the strength
強度に影響します
Humans probably do
人間もおそらくそうだろう
Talk about to the extent
程度の話はする
Good and good, to the extent of the day
良くも悪くも、その日の範囲内で
It will take 10 years for you to have a new situation
新しい状況になるには10年かかるだろう
Then Secretary Wu will tell you today that history has not ended
そうすればウー長官は今日、歴史は終わっていないことを告げるだろう
It's not like Heige said
ヘイジの言う通りじゃないよ
The history of NLP history does not end
NLPの歴史は終わらない
meaning keeps changing
意味は変わり続ける
So the political situation in Taiwan
さて、台湾の政治情勢ですが、
Line of entry with competitive style
競争力のあるスタイルのエントリーライン
has been changing
変化してきた
what's next
次は何ですか
we listen now
私たちは今聞いています
A Discussion by Secretary Wu of the Institute of Political Science
政治研究所の呉書記によるディスカッション
you applause
あなたは拍手します
Thank you Vice President Wang
王副社長に感謝します
Also glad to have today
私も今日を迎えられてとても嬉しいです
so many listeners
とても多くのリスナー
interested in this topic
このトピックに興味がある
then i
その後私は
I think the way I'm going to talk about this today
今日これについて話す方法は次のとおりだと思います
On the one hand, it is based on my observation of some theories on this topic
一方で、これはこのトピックに関するいくつかの理論についての私の観察に基づいています。
On the one hand, I want to connect this issue with those around us.
一方で、私はこの問題を私たちの周囲の人々と結び付けたいと考えています。
This political phenomenon that everyone has personally experienced is combined
誰もが経験したこの政治現象が組み合わさって、
I'll try my best
がんばります
Then I hope everyone can put forward your views and this question
それでは、皆さんがあなたの意見とこの質問を提案していただければ幸いです
When this person talks about a paragraph, let's discuss it together
この人が段落について話したら、一緒に話し合いましょう
The topic I want to talk about today is
今日話したいテーマは
From identity to economy
アイデンティティから経済へ
It is the axis transformation of Taiwan's political competition
それは台湾の政治競争の軸の転換である
Before I start, let me ask you to look at the two sets of pictures
始める前に、2 組の写真を見ていただきたいと思います。
then i won't say much
それなら多くは言いません
When you look at this picture
この写真を見ると
Maybe it will provide some of your memories and some feelings
もしかしたらそれはあなたの思い出や感情を提供してくれるかもしれません
Because we have brought meaning from these two sets of pictures, let’s talk about
この 2 組の写真から意味を引き出したので、次について話しましょう。
Let's see it as a melting point of water
水の融点として見てみましょう
These are all things that happened to everyone
これらはすべて誰にでも起こったことです
The central government and Taipei City have different views on this matter
この件に関して中央政府と台北市は見解が異なる
I remember this scene
このシーンを思い出します
feel this cartoon
この漫画を感じてください
take this comic
この漫画を手に取ってください
It turns out that the same direction of President Chiang
蒋介石総統も同じ方向性であることが判明
All concentrated in the mainland of Taoyuan
すべて桃園本土に集中
Daxi went
大喜は行きました
if someone has visited
誰かが訪れたなら
All kinds of fellow countrymen are there
あらゆる種類の同胞がそこにいます
This is a series of induced movements
これは一連の誘発された動きです
medium oil
中油
ship
船
In fact, when everyone was flat
実際、誰もがフラットだったとき
we had a time
私たちは時間があった
That stamp is called Taiwan stamp
その切手は台湾切手と呼ばれています
Later Ma Ying-jeou came up
その後、馬英九が登場した
It became the stamp of the Republic of China again
またまた中華民国の切手になりました
It's a huge movement
大変な動きですね
ok then we all have to look down now
よし、じゃあみんなで下を向く必要がある
Ma Ying-jeou period
馬英九時代
since 2008
2008年以来
Fumao, there was a debate and now it's cancelled.
ふまお、議論がありましたが、現在は中止されています。
But of course it's still very controversial
しかし、もちろん、それは依然として非常に物議を醸しています
Some people even think that the fight between the two gentlemen Ma and Wang has something to do with this
マー氏とワン氏の二人の戦いがこれと関係があるとさえ考える人もいる
Dismantle the earth today, tear down the government tomorrow
今日地球を解体し、明日には政府を解体する
This catchphrase reminds everyone
このキャッチフレーズは誰にでも思い出させます
This is the electric palm
これが電動パームです
at the end of last year
昨年末に
This wave of military education
この軍事教育の波
Of course, it's also related to my husband.
もちろん夫のことも関係しています。
earn tax together
一緒に税金を稼ぐ
down a minister
大臣を失墜させる
The report is now almost dead
このレポートは現在ほぼ死滅している
good
良い
Okay, these two sets of pictures
さて、この二組の写真
Here's to the two presidents
二人の大統領に挨拶します
era period
時代時期
different social controversies
さまざまな社会論争
what did we see
私たちは何を見たのか
Let's start with these two sets of graphs
これら 2 つのグラフのセットから始めましょう
we look at any society
私たちはどんな社会を見ても
there is a way to understand it
それを理解する方法があります
That's where Clubwich is
そこがクラブウィッチです
Basically we can divide into three types
基本的には3つのタイプに分けられます
a prematter
事前事項
one is matter and one is post matter
1 つは問題で、もう 1 つは事後です
In fact, how much is according to the new formula
実際、新しい計算式によればいくらになりますか
differentiated by historical development
歴史的発展によって区別される
The former material Primitillist speaks of
プリミティリストが語るかつての素材
ethnic group religion
民族宗教
It's very basic, very traditional
それはとても基本的で、とても伝統的なものです
on the industrial side no
産業面ではいいえ
before coming
来る前に
matter left and right
左右の問題
So let's go into more detail
それでは、さらに詳しく見ていきましょう
Basically because after the revolution came
基本的には革命が起こった後だから
modern society
現代社会
In modern society, it is easy to divide into labor and capital
現代社会は労働と資本に分断されやすい
then this country
それからこの国
in this economy
この経済では
what kind of position
どのような立場ですか
it actively intervenes
積極的に介入する
Because the market is under-allocated
市場の割り当てが不足しているため
Not even allowing the market to be replaced
市場の代替さえも許さない
this is socialism
これは社会主義です
or should it basically
それとも基本的にそうすべきですか
respect all property
すべての財産を尊重する
Then this Qing Liao robbed the rich
そしてこの青遼は金持ちから強盗をした
Let the market do its thing
市場に任せましょう
To create wealth for everyone
すべての人に富を生み出すために
These two different views are divided into left and right
これら 2 つの異なるビューは左と右に分かれています
The Age of the Afterlife
死後の世界の時代
It's the environment, for example, the Lu Party
それは環境、たとえば魯党です。
or gender politics and so on
あるいはジェンダー政治など
In the west we find
西では私たちが見つけます
It is dominated by material differences
それは物質的な違いによって支配されます
Here comes the industrial revolution
産業革命の到来
Positive differentiation occurs
積極的な差別化が起こる
different actors then have their own interests
さまざまな俳優がそれぞれの興味を持っています
The biggest controversy is what I just said
最大の論争は今言われたばかりです
The role of the state in economic life
経済生活における国家の役割
The so-called leftists mean that the state wants to intervene
いわゆる左派は国家が介入したいということを意味する
That is to say, it is better for the state to intervene less
つまり国家の介入は少ないほうが良いということだ
this in the present west
ここは今、西側にある
still the main axis of competition
依然として競争の主軸
It's interesting
それは面白い
in western countries
西側諸国では
Almost always make a distinction between left and right
ほとんどの場合、左右の区別がつきます
so like in america
アメリカのように
it compares to the left
左と比べると
Of course, the United States as a whole is relatively right.
もちろん、米国全体としては比較的正しい。
But it is relatively left
でも比較的残ってる
is the Democratic Party
民主党です
right is republican
右は共和党です
Britain is more left
イギリスは左派のほうが多い
Is the public party
公的なパーティーですか
Paulista on the right
右がパウリスタ
There's a Lipdance over here
ここにリップダンスがあります
That right said it was in Germany
そうだ、ドイツにあると言うのだ
Just had a general election, right?
ちょうど総選挙がありましたよね？
To the left are the Social Democrats
左派は社民党
right
右
The right might be the Christian Democrats
右派はキリスト教民主党かもしれない
this
これ
have such competing spindles
このような競合するスピンドルがある
Political parties divide along this society
この社会では政党が分裂している
Collecting position
採取立場
If the party
パーティーなら
words that ignore major social divides
大きな社会的分断を無視した言葉
its political influence will be weakened
その政治的影響力は弱まるだろう
Now everyone is arguing about one thing
今、みんなが一つのことについて議論している
then i jumped out
それから私は飛び出しました
make a claim
主張する
no one knows what i'm doing
誰も私が何をしているのか知りません
They will quarrel with him today
彼らは今日彼と喧嘩するだろう
Your political influence is gone
あなたの政治的影響力はなくなった
in western countries
西側諸国では
Prominence of material divergence
材料の相違の顕著性
is the majority party
多数党です
take left and right positions
都要採取左右的立場
Of course in some cases
もちろん場合によっては
can still see
まだ見える
pre-substance divergence
物質の発散前
for example
例えば
will be held in 2014
2014年に開催されます
Is it from the UK
イギリスからですか
It should be said United Kingdom
イギリスと言うべきか
independent scotland
独立したスコットランド
for example
例えば
in mainland spain to catalonia
スペイン本土からカタルーニャまで
It's from Barcelona
バルセロナからです
it is strongly independent
それは強い独立性を持っています
this tendency
この傾向
Kerbac in Canada
カナダのケルバック
There has always been such a trend
昔からそういう傾向はあったよ
France also has
フランスにもある
But basically
でも基本的には
those are the few main ones
それらはいくつかの主要なものです
still around
まだ周りにあります
But in selfish democracies
しかし利己的な民主主義では
This is not the case anymore
もうそんなことはありません
Because of the social divisions in many of these countries
これらの国の多くには社会的分断があるため、
it may be latent
それは潜在的なものかもしれない
good
良い
if there is
もしあるなら
specific social divisions
特定の社会的区分
then you will have
そうすればあなたは持っています
Certainly the party system
確かにパーティシステム
with it
それと
Your social divide on the left
左派の社会的分断
You'll be a party of the left and the right
あなたは左派と右派の当事者になるでしょう
if say your
あなたの言うなら
society has experienced some
社会はいくつかのことを経験しました
major development
大きな発展
it may change
変わるかもしれない
One even
偶数 1 つ
bring out new social divisions
新たな社会的分断を引き起こす
Social divisions may change
社会の分断は変わるかもしれない
no
いいえ
never change
決して変わらない
So the new social pit period
新しい社会のピット期間
May replace old divergence
古い分岐を置き換える可能性があります
or the old one here
またはここの古いもの
Separate the symphony after the new one appears
新しい交響曲が登場した後に交響曲を分離する
then exist together
それから一緒に存在してください
Political parties have to chase votes, right?
政党は票を追わないといけないですよね？
so he has to pay close attention
だから彼は細心の注意を払わなければならない
Is there a new topic
新しい話題はありますか
Is there a new disagreement
新たな違いはありますか?
So it appeared
それで現れたのは
Party redirection through elections
選挙による政党の方向転換
his
他的
The reason why his political party will follow the divide
彼の政党が分裂に従う理由
Going because he wants votes
票が欲しいから行く
Then the difference is decided
それで差が決まる
What is the society most concerned about
社会が最も懸念していることは何ですか
so you have to follow him around
だからあなたは彼の後を追いかけなければなりません
let me give you an example
例をあげましょう
In the UK the Conservative Party is called Toy
イギリスでは保守党のことを「おもちゃ」と呼ぶ
Historically he was a royalist
歴史的に彼は王党派だった
Of course it is impossible to imagine now
もちろん今では考えられない
there will be a party in england
イギリスでパーティーが開かれます
He asserted that the king's right is still the greatest
彼は国王の権利が依然として最大であると主張した
This Toy has become a white-handed political party
このおもちゃは白人の政党になった
so he has to follow this
だから彼はこれに従わなければならない
Time changes with the development of this history
この歴史の発展とともに時代は変わる
So social divisions change
社会的な分断が変化する
Political parties follow it
政党もそれに従う
So a social divide turns into a new political divide
社会的分断が新たな政治的分断に変わる
Let's take a closer look at how this process came about.
このプロセスがどのようにして生まれたのかを詳しく見てみましょう。
Do you think some of the political parties are more innovative?
一部の政党はより革新的だと思いますか?
it adjusts its position
それは位置を調整します
then it wins the election
それで選挙に勝つ
why ? because new differences have arisen
なぜですか? 新たな違いが生じたからです
Laggards will be under strong pressure
出遅れた企業は強いプレッシャーにさらされるだろう
he also has to adjust
彼も調整しなければならない
Because someone has changed
誰かが変わったから
you have to change
あなたは変わらなければなりません
no way to adjust
調整する方法がありません
will lose votes
票を失うだろう
Even the party is gone
パーティーすらなくなってしまった
It's a thief
泥棒だよ
fit for party survival
パーティーの生き残りに適している
Everyone knows that I am based on what Darwin said in biology.
私が生物学でダーウィンが言ったことに基づいていることは誰もが知っています。
It's a thief
泥棒だよ
fit survival
適合生存
the party
パーティー
can have several results
いくつかの結果が得られる
One is the original political party is still maintained
1つは、元の政党がまだ維持されていることです。
But the party has actually changed
でも実は党は変わってしまった
It's as if the Royalists in England have now become the Conservatives
あたかもイギリスの王党派が今や保守党になったかのようだ
So we see that these parties are still competing on the table
したがって、これらの政党はまだテーブルで競争していることがわかります
But it's really a new issue
しかし、それは本当に新しい問題です
new differences
新しい違い
Or there is a new political party
あるいは新しい政党ができた
replaced the old party
古い党を置き換えた
so let me say something first
だから最初に一言言わせてください
What we see today is like what Vice President Wang just mentioned
私たちが今日目にしているのは、王副主席が先ほど述べたようなものです。
what we see now
私たちが今見ているもの
profit blue profit
利益青の利益
Kuomintang Democratic Progressive Party
国民党・民進党
Then they argue about something
それから彼らは何かについて議論します
then we feel
それから私たちは感じます
Wow, it's been like this for so many years
うーん、もう何年もこんな感じです
nothing
なし
Social divides can change
社会的格差は変化する可能性がある
And when social divisions change
そして社会の分断が変わるとき
Political parties must follow suit
政党もそれに倣わなければならない
otherwise
さもないと
he might disappear
彼は消えるかもしれない
die out
消える
ok then let's look down
よし、じゃあ下を見てみよう
What is Taiwan like?
台湾ってどんなところ？
In the 1980s, Morgan's early nineties
1980 年代、モーガンの 90 年代初頭
Taiwan's democracy
台湾の民主主義
There are two social divides
社会には2つの分断がある
competing with each other
互いに競い合う
I remember very clearly
とても鮮明に覚えています
At that time, I happened to be from this
その時、私はたまたまここから来ました
Desu Xuele
デス・シュエレ
When preparing to return to Taiwan
台湾への帰国準備の際
Because then I'll keep an eye on it
それなら私が見守ってあげるから
Taiwan's democracy has only just begun to emerge
台湾の民主主義はまだ芽生え始めたばかり
What kind of democracy will people treat you
人々はあなたをどのような民主主義として扱うでしょうか
Will there be class differences?
階級差はあるのでしょうか？
Western countries are like this
西洋諸国はこんな感じ
and leftists and rightists
そして左翼と右翼
There will also be leftists and rightists here in Taiwan
ここ台湾にも左翼と右翼が存在するだろう
Then why is there such a thing
ではなぜそんな事があるのか
because it makes sense
それは理にかなっているから
Because the Kuomintang has been pursuing the pursuit of excellence in industry and commerce for many years
それは国民党が長年にわたって工業と商業の卓越性の追求を追求してきたからである。
Economic Development Policy Based on Growth
成長を基盤とした経済発展政策
At the same time trade unions are suppressed
同時に労働組合も弾圧される
we call this
私たちはこれをそう呼んでいます
developed capitalist countries
先進資本主義諸国
Captive Developmental State
捕虜の発達状態
So like this come more up
だからこのようにもっと上に来てください
you now have political power
あなたは今政治的権力を持っています
Yes, during that time we saw
はい、その間に私たちは見ました
sport with some features
いくつかの機能を備えたスポーツ
i was studying in berkland
私はバークランドで勉強していました
I found that there are many people who do functions
関数を実行している人がたくさんいることがわかりました
went to berkland to give a speech
スピーチをするためにバークランドに行きました
I go to listen to every game
毎試合観戦に行ってます
do you remember
覚えていますか
At that time, the disciples also had a very powerful
当時、弟子たちも非常に強力な力を持っていました。
this circular demonstration
この循環デモ
and burned something
そして何かを燃やした
Then opposed the policy at the time
そして当時の政策に反対した
democracy is coming
民主主義がやってくる
All kinds of social voices have risen
社会的なあらゆる声が高まっている
Will this power come out?
この力が出てくるのか？
or
また
Subgroup-Based Identity Analysis
サブグループベースのアイデンティティ分析
Subgroup sub-asnik
サブグループサブアスニック
because usually we don't think
なぜなら通常私たちは考えないからです
Han people in Taiwan
台湾の漢民族
Have a way with each other asnik
お互いに仲良くしてください
such a difference
そんな違い
but it does make a difference
しかしそれは違いを生みます
Usually called sub-asnik
通常はサブアスニックと呼ばれます
In Taiwan, we will talk about provincial conflicts
台湾では地方紛争について話します
is it that thing
それはそれですか
Because the Democratic Party has always emphasized
民主党がずっと強調してるから
It is the resistance of the Chinese nation
それは中華民族の抵抗だ
outside the party
パーティーの外で
what is emphasized
何が強調されているのか
Taiwan's Subjective Consciousness
台湾の主観的意識
this is also a conflict
これも争いだ
So when you democratize
だから民主化すると
Many things were suppressed
いろんなものが抑圧された
now democratized
今は民主化された
So what will emerge
それで何が現れるのか
a social divide
社会的分断
We found that as a result of later development
その後の開発の結果、
Identity politics trumps class and distribution
アイデンティティ政治が階級と分配に優先する
over twenty years
20年以上
The Axis of Taiwan's Political Competition
台湾の政治的競争の軸
from the 1990s to the 2000s
1990年代から2000年代まで
A tacit understanding until the 2000s
2000年代までは暗黙の了解
it's all like this
全部こんな感じです
Taiwan is a very interesting phenomenon
台湾は非常に興味深い現象です
Because people are people in Taiwan politics
台湾の政治では人は人だから
can feel
感じることができる
we are not so easy
私たちはそれほど簡単ではありません
To talk to the Western democratic system
西側の民主主義制度と対話する
why? because they are left and right
どうして? 左右にあるから
we are agree
私達は同意します
You know what the UK says about identity
イギリスがアイデンティティについて何と言っているか知っていますか
Of course Scotland can have these
もちろんスコットランドにもこれらはあります
Axis of Basic Political Competition
基本的な政治的競争の軸
not agreeing with this phenomenon
この現象には同意しません
America is the same
アメリカも同じだ
But we are agreeing
しかし、私たちは同意しています
we talk less
私たちは話すことが少なくなります
class
階級
So I agree with Duxiu
だから私もDuxiuさんの意見に同意します
Absence of left and right
左右が無い
No Influential Leftist Party Emerged in Taiwan
台湾では有力な左翼政党が誕生せず
who are we
私たちは誰ですか
do we have a communist party
共産党はありますか
Yes, I have
はい、持っています
We can often see a red flag on the street
道路で赤旗をよく見かけます
and then there in the fifties
そして50年代には
That song is quite majestic
その曲はとても雄大です
all the way past
ずっと過去の
no one knows what he sings
彼が何を歌っているのか誰も知りません
Then the red flag is waving
そのとき赤旗が振られています
that's all
それで全部です
we have the labor party
私たちには労働党があります
That's not really a leftist party either.
それも本当の左翼政党ではありません。
in our congress
私たちの議会では
no real leftist parties
本当の左翼政党は存在しない
Opposition to the KMT
国民党に反対する
later became the Democratic Party
後に民主党となった
he didn't adopt the platform of a party of the left
彼は左翼政党の綱領を採用しなかった
we don't have any major political parties
私たちには主要な政党がありません
group as socialism
社会主義としての集団
deep group socialism
深い集団社会主義
by western standards
西洋の基準からすると
Taiwan's main political parties are left and right in ideology
台湾の主要政党にはイデオロギーにおいて左右がある
right-handed on the spectrum
スペクトル上では右利き
but our right
しかし私たちの権利
no ideological claims
イデオロギー的な主張はありません
let me give you an example
例をあげましょう
private property
私有財産
Property-wise is a very important thing
財産面は非常に重要なことです
is extremely sacred
非常に神聖なものです
we don't feel that way either
私たちもそうは感じません
It's basically a matter of left and right
基本的には左右の問題です
Disagreement in Taiwan
台湾での意見の相違
That is undetdeveloped
それは未開発です
we don't have that language
私たちはその言語を持っていません
we don't have that concept
私たちにはその概念がありません
we don't have that awareness
私たちにはその認識がありません
isn't it good
いいじゃないですか
seems to be good
良いようです
but we replace it with something else
しかし、私たちはそれを別のものに置き換えます
we have two bourgeois parties
私たちには二つのブルジョワ政党がある
KMT strengthens ties with factories
国民党、工場との連携を強化
yes
はい
The DPP also has its own donors and money veins
民進党にも独自の献金者と資金脈がある
electoral competition brings
選挙戦がもたらすもの
Huge need for political cash
莫大な政治資金が必要
underdeveloped trade unions
未発達な労働組合
no way to party
パーティーする方法がない
provide financial assistance
提供財政意助
We see election competition costs money
選挙戦にはお金がかかることがわかりました
right
右
where does the money come from
お金はどこから来るのですか
Of course the money comes from the rich
もちろんお金は富裕層から来ます
so it looks like
だからそれはのように見える
Big business of course
もちろん大企業
bourgeoisie to prop
ブルジョワジーが小道具にする
But if you have a
しかし、あなたが持っているなら、
words of a strong union
強い団結の言葉
trade unions can be held accountable
労働組合は責任を問われる可能性がある
his own strength to support the party
彼自身の力で党を支える
I think it's good
良いと思います
because it's happening now
それが今起きているから
british labor party
英国労働党
In the long run, we will go together with the trade union
長期的には労働組合と協力していきます
why
なぜ
Because of the British trade unions
イギリスの労働組合のせいで
the membership they paid
彼らが支払った会費
Fees automatically become a source of funding for the Labor Party
手数料は自動的に労働党の資金源となる
Now this represents
さて、これは次のことを表します
british labor party leader
英国労働党党首
I want to change the country and cut this off
国を変えてこれを断ち切りたい
many people are shocked
多くの人がショックを受けています
So if you do this
それでこれをやると
So where does our Labor Party get its money from?
それでは、私たちの労働党はどこから資金を得ているのでしょうか？
It is not conceivable at least so far
少なくとも今のところは考えられない
If the Labor Party, the Labor Party
労働党なら労働党
its source of funding
その資金源
A big part comes from joining the union
大きな部分は労働組合への参加によるものです
money donated by people
人々が寄付したお金
dues paid
支払われた会費
Of course it has to reflect the interests of workers
もちろん労働者の利益を反映する必要がある
Right
右
But our trade union is very naive
しかし、私たちの労働組合は非常に世間知らずです
Because of course there is no union like that
もちろんそんな組合はないから
I don't have that kind of wealth
そんな財産ないよ
So when this party is competing
つまり、このパーティーが競合しているとき
As long as you have money, you can suppress it with both sides
金さえあれば双方で抑えられる
so it produces
それでそれは生成します
There is also a lack of control over political cash
政治資金の管理も欠如している
The business community has a strong lobbying industry
ビジネス界には強力なロビー活動がある
I think we have six business products, right?
ビジネス製品は 6 つあると思います。
Type of work, type of business, industrial and commercial cooperation, industrial cooperation
職種、業種、商工連携、産業連携
small business
小規模なビジネス
electricity electricity
電電電
One is better than the other
一方が他方よりも優れている
when you need the funds
資金が必要なとき
You must ask them for help
あなたは彼らに助けを求めなければなりません
Business and industry are closely related to the brain
ビジネスや産業は脳と密接な関係がある
Let's play golf together, right?
一緒にゴルフをしませんか？
So social welfare increases
それで社会福祉が増える
like
好き
This is an unreasonable taste
これは無茶苦茶な味だ
But in fact it does not reflect the politics of ruthlessness
しかし実際には、それは冷酷な政治を反映しているわけではありません
or you are
それともあなたは
You also have to give some benefits to your constituency
選挙区に何らかの利益を与える必要もあります
I also want to give some benefits to my constituency
私も選挙区に何らかの恩恵を与えたい
so i also
だから私も
Help you to transfer part of the money to your constituency
お金の一部を選挙区に送金するのを手伝ってください
You also let me define where there are some funding places
資金調達先がどこにあるのかも定義させてください
Then I don't know where the money will go
そうなるとお金はどこへ行くか分かりません
What method is used to send it out?
どのような方法で発送されますか？
Handicrafts in some places
場所によっては手工芸品が多い
what road construction
何の道路工事だ
what to do
何をすべきか
Flooding with hand power
ハンドパワーによる浸水
so
それで
So actually two bourgeois parties
つまり実際には 2 つのブルジョア政党
it has a reason
それには理由があります
Because of the sustained high-speed economic development in the past
過去の高度経済発展の持続により、
because our society moves
私たちの社会は動いているから
The ratings of social mobility are very high
ソーシャルモビリティの評価は非常に高い
Our education has a strong equalizing effect
私たちの教育には強い平等化効果があります
This makes your
これにより、
The structure of this class is highly mobile
このクラスの構造は非常に可動性が高く、
It is no longer easy to generate economic awareness
経済意識を高めるのはもはや簡単ではない
Your parents may actually be third-level reviewers.
あなたの両親は実際には第 3 レベルの審査員である可能性があります。
And you have become our lawyer
そしてあなたは私たちの弁護士になりました
Where is your class consciousness?
あなたの階級意識はどこにありますか？
Bayi's incomplete class consciousness
バイの不完全な階級意識
It is an industry dominated by small and medium-sized enterprises
中小企業が多くを占める業界です
it turned out to be interesting
面白いことが分かりました
Because Taiwan is very different from South Korea and Japan
台湾は韓国や日本とは大きく違うので
South Korea is big business
韓国は大企業だ
Japan can have a dual economy
日本は二重経済を実現できる
There are large enterprises and small and medium enterprises
大企業も中小企業もある
Taiwan is dominated by small and medium-sized enterprises
台湾は中小企業が大多数を占めている
Taiwan's big companies don't look big in the world
台湾の大企業は世界的には大きく見えない
Foxconn exception
Foxconn の例外
Therefore, the adverse impact on the development of the labor movement
したがって、労働運動の発展に悪影響を及ぼす可能性がある。
SMEs are particularly hostile to trade unions
中小企業は特に労働組合に対して敵対的である
However, it is easier for trade unions to mobilize and organize in a large enterprise environment.
しかし、大企業の環境では労働組合が結集し、組織するのが容易です。
politics of course repress it
もちろん政治はそれを弾圧する
So if we compare it with East Asia
東アジアと比較してみると
You will find that P class politics in East Asian countries in general are not so obvious
一般的に東アジア諸国における P 層の政治はそれほど明白ではないことがわかるでしょう。
However, compared with Japan and South Korea, the labor movement in Taiwan is especially compared with South Korea.
しかし、日本や韓国と比較すると、台湾の労働運動は特に韓国と比較される。
so we the left are absent
だから我々左翼は不在だ
that's not left and right that's what we are
それは左でも右でもない、それが私たちなのです
Political parties do not use left-right policies to win votes
政党は票を獲得するために左右の政策を利用しない
Rather, political competition is waged by the mobilization of opposing identities
むしろ、政治的競争は、対立するアイデンティティを動員することによって行われます。
what are we looking at now
私たちは今何を見ているのですか
how do we see history
私たちは歴史をどう見るか
what are we going to do now
どうしましょう
what will the future be
将来はどうなるでしょうか
let's look at history first
まずは歴史を見てみましょう
History necessarily involves different times in textbooks
教科書では歴史には必ず異なる時代が登場する
Is it a continental or oceanic view of history?
それは大陸的な歴史観ですか、それとも海洋的な歴史観ですか?
We think of Taiwan as an extension of the mainland
私たちは台湾を本土の延長として考えています
In other words, Taiwan is a child of the ocean
言い換えれば、台湾は海の子です
you are from a continent
あなたは大陸の出身です
Taiwan from Mainland China's point of view
中国本土から見た台湾
Or regard Taiwan as
あるいは台湾を次のようにみなします
yourself as the center
自分が中心になって
then a marine
それから海兵隊員
Then there's the influence of the ocean
あとは海の影響ですね
There is an influence from the mainland
大陸からの影響もある
Is it human or land
それは人間ですか、それとも土地ですか
You strongly belong to this group
あなたはこのグループに強く属しています
It is basically the Chinese nation
基本的には中華民族です
is from Zhongyuan
中原出身です
is this
これは
still a territory
まだ領土
this is not right
これは正しくない
Taiwan is right.
台湾は正しい
different people come
いろんな人が来ます
Right
右
The Japanese come, the Dutch come, the Chinese come, etc.
日本人が来る、オランダ人が来る、中国人が来るなど。
but the center of your land
でもあなたの土地の中心
what is wrong with this kind of thing
こんなことの何が問題なのか
It depends on what point of view you take
どの観点からそれを意味するかによって異なります
Just your most hyped Rijiu Garden
最も誇大宣伝されているリジュ ガーデン
A real point in the middle of Rijiu Garden
日州庭園の真ん中にあるまさにポイント
Is it Japanese data?
日本のデータですか？
what does japan mean
日本とはどういう意味ですか
It's unreasonable for the Japanese to call you
日本人があなたに電話するのは無理です
don't give him legitimacy
彼に正当性を与えないでください
why not give him legitimacy
なぜ彼に正当性を与えないのか
because of this place
この場所のせいで
It is harmful to the Chinese people and the Chinese people
それは中国人と中国人にとって有害で​​す
so it's not legal for him to come
だから彼が来るのは合法ではない
Turning to this point of view of the Republic of China
中華民国のこの視点に目を向けると
expected
期待される
It can also be said that the rule itself
ルールそのものとも言える
have a good meaning
良い意味がある
or at least you can put him
あるいは少なくともあなたは彼を置くことができます
cleanup
掃除
different times anyway
とにかく時間が違う
Some from here, some from there
いくつかはここに、いくつかはあそこに
There are those from the north and those from the west.
北から来たものと西から来たものがあります。
this is the middle period
これは中期です
value-neutral
価値中立
but value neutral
しかし中立的な価値観
In fact, all the rulers
実際、すべての統治者は、
relativized
相対化された
Because he actually has two different views
なぜなら彼は実際には二つの異なる見解を持っているからです
What he reflects is the view of continental and oceanic history
彼が反映しているのは大陸と海洋の歴史の見方です
Humanism is not the same as territorialism
ヒューマニズムは領土主義と同じではない
now how do we see now
今、私たちは今をどう見ていますか
is to say the official way
つまり正式な方法です
we are a divided country
私たちは分断された国です
We claim sovereignty over the other side
私たちは相手側に対する主権を主張します
Because we are inferior to him
私たちは彼より劣っているから
He claims sovereignty over us
彼は私たちに対する主権を主張している
because of lack of power
力不足のため
not only us
私たちだけではありません
So now it's a divided country
だから今は分断された国だよ
Is this how you see it?
こう見えますか？
still one country
まだ一つの国
There are two views on one side of the country
この国の片側には 2 つの景色があります
one side is
片側は
Am I completely unacceptable to the Republic of China?
私は中華民国にとってまったく受け入れられないのでしょうか？
Another one is
もう一つは、
ok i accept for now
わかりました、今のところ受け入れます
Republic of China
中華民国
But it is the name of Taiwan now
しかし今では台湾の名前になっています。
We have no legal relationship with the other side
当社は相手方と法的関係はありません
This Republic of China is Taiwan
この中華民国は台湾です
what is that?
それは何ですか？
What are we now?
私たちは今何ですか？
Different cultural experience also different views
文化体験が違えば見方も違う
future
未来
Are you going to unify?
統一するつもりですか？
Will it continue to maintain the holy school?
これからも神聖な学校を維持していくのでしょうか？
Prove Taiwan's independence
台湾の独立を証明するために
Are you in Jianguo?
建国にいるの？
different people have different opinions
さまざまな人がさまざまな意見を持っています
Aren't we a fun place?
私たちは楽しい場所ではありませんか？
We are very basic with these
私たちはこれらについて非常に基本的なことを行っています
for many countries
多くの国にとって
It's a natural thing to do
それは当然のことです
we disagree
私たちは同意しません
Because you agree that nature is different
自然は違うということにあなたも同意するから
the identity, if it is the main social divide
アイデンティティ（それが主要な社会的分断である場合）
The main axis of our political competition is of course different
政治的競争の主軸はもちろん違います
Since the late 2000s
2000年代後半以降
This is an important point and point of view I want to raise
これは私が提起したい重要な点であり視点です
Because we've been on this identification
私たちはこのアイデンティティを貫いてきたから
argued for a long time
長い間議論した
this is almost 20 years old
これはもうすぐ20年になります
It is the front half of the inner main picture we just looked at
先ほど見た内側のメイン画像の前半部分です
The main axis of political competition begins to shift, I think it is called paradise shift
政治的競争の主軸が変わり始める、それをパラダイスシフトと呼ぶと思います
It's a paradigm shift
それはパラダイムシフトです
why?
なぜ？
Because economic growth has slowed
経済成長が鈍化したため
Therefore, people's desire for basic life has increased
したがって、人々の基本的な生活への欲求は高まっています
The era of high growth has entered and will never return
高度成長時代はもう戻らない
But if it's our age
でも、私たちの年齢だと
It was during the period of economic take-off
当時は経済の離陸期でした
We may think that Ah Star capital raised
ああスター資本が調達したと考えられるかもしれません
economic growth
経済成長
is a natural thing
自然なことです
But our time was like this
でも僕らの時代はこんな感じだった
this age
この年齢
young people from different professions
さまざまな職業の若者たち
He doesn't think and feel that way at all.
彼はそのように考えたり感じたりすることはまったくありません。
my daughter complains to me
娘が私に文句を言う
His daughter was alive and well
彼の娘は元気に生きていた
i heard he worked hard
彼は一生懸命働いたと聞いた
I heard how to tell him
彼に伝える方法を聞きました
22K right?
22Kですよね？
and how many years
そして何年
There is no salary increase at this time
現時点では昇給はありません
So the situation in that economy is very different
つまり、その経済の状況は大きく異なります
After the age of identity politics has passed
アイデンティティ政治の時代が過ぎた後
everyone is tired
誰もが疲れています
Identifying with something is deep in your heart
何かとの同一化は心の奥深くにある
maybe when i was very young
おそらく若い頃
grown up in the family
家族の中で育った
Because I keep picking that thing
それを選び続けるから
it's very uncomfortable
とても不快です
third
三番目
Wait a minute, I want to talk about this
これについては後ほど説明します。
cross-strait relations
海峡両岸関係
Identity is a bridge between identity and economy
アイデンティティはアイデンティティと経済の間の架け橋です
Anyway, there are several main reasons
とにかく、主な理由はいくつかあります
Axis shift
軸シフト
process first
最初に処理する
New social divisions appear to be emerging
新たな社会的分断が生じているようだ
the second
二番目
The KMT has changed after losing the election
国民党は選挙に負けて変わった
third
三番目
The Democratic Progressive Party has also transformed under the pressure of the election
民進党も選挙の圧力で変貌
Let's take a closer look
もっと詳しく見てみましょう
what am i talking about
私は何を話しているのですか
Let's take a look at the state of the economy
経済の状況を見てみましょう
how the economy is doing
経済はどうなっているのか
The average economic growth rate in the 1990s was 6.93%
1990年代の平均経済成長率は6.93%でした
Everyone at that time
あの時のみんな
I saw numbers in the 1990s and felt
1990年代の数字を見て感じた
not so good
あまりよくない
The 1980s were double-digit growth
1980年代は2桁の成長を遂げた
2000 to 2007
2000年から2007年
satisfy the ruling
判決を満足させる
During the period when the governance point was in power
統治点が権力を握っていた時代
From 2007 to 2008, half of them were in power under the KMT
2007 年から 2008 年にかけて、その半数が国民党政権下で政権を握った
At that time it was adjusted to 4.43%
当時は4.43％に調整されていた
KMT slams DPP
国民党が民進党を非難
total economy
トータルエコノミー
Of course it only goes up and down
もちろん上がったり下がったりするだけですが
it's not average that way
それは平均的ではありません
2008 to 2011 or 2012
2008 年から 2011 年または 2012 年まで
These data are sometimes 100 million and sometimes 12
これらのデータは 1 億の場合もあれば、12 の場合もあります
adjusted to 3.2%
3.2%に調整
what do we hear now
今何を聞いていますか
Baoer, right?
バオエル、そうですよね？
Poichi
ポイチ
Wenwen grew up in the 1980s
ウェンウェンは 1980 年代に育ちました
Have you ever heard of such numbers?
そのような数字を聞いたことがありますか?
but that's how it is now isn't it
でも今はそうなんですよね
Strongly narrate
力強く語る
minimum is 0
最小値は0です
Maximum is 1
最大値は 1
it is coming
来ている
measure your income inequality
収入の不平等を測る
If it is 0, it is the most equal
0なら最も等しい
If it is 1, it is the most unequal
1 の場合、最も不平等です
We see strong narrative
強力な物語が見られます
9.0.317
９。０。３１７
0.1 to 0.7 years is 0.34
0.1～0.7年は0.34
Then continue to grow to 0.343
その後、0.343 まで増加し続けます。
this looks
これは見た目
can't match the feeling
気持ちが合わない
Because it doesn't change much
あまり変わらないので
We see why indexing is good
インデックス作成が良い理由がわかりました
This is our coefficient for Dabao
これはダバオの係数です
Dabao coefficient is generally understood by everyone
ダバオ係数は一般的に誰もが理解しています
It's the one with the highest income
一番収入が高い人だよ
20%
２０％
The ratio between the bottom 2%
下位2%の割合
most powerful group
最も強力なグループ
Liqun
リクン
Its income is worse than the original
以前より収入が悪くなった
how much to add
どれくらい追加するか
good
良い
1690s is 5.33
1690年代は5.33です
2002 706.03
2002年706.03
2008 to 2011 is 6.19
2008 年から 2011 年は 6.19
keep going up
上がり続ける
Compare the above with international
上記を国際的なものと比較してください
come and see
見に来て
compared to Japan
日本と比べて
Already relatively speaking
すでに相対的に言えば
is not equal
等しくありません
South Korea pulls higher than ours
韓国は我が国よりも高い水準にある
Americanization
アメリカナイゼーション
Of course it's more scary
もちろんもっと怖いです
because it is more capitalist
そのほうが資本主義的だから
its large island coefficient
その大きな島係数
if singapore
シンガポールなら
up to 20
20まで
this number is very large
この数は非常に大きいです
but in our case
しかし私たちの場合は
is also changing
も変化しています
Unemployment rate 2.043.7
失業率 2.043.7
4.77
４。７７
Unemployment is constantly increasing
失業者は増え続けている
So this graph of the economy
この経済グラフは
Bottom Natural Member Home
ボトムナチュラルメンバーホーム
is the case of an interest rate economy
それは金利経済の場合です
so we showed up
それで私たちは現れました
triple phenomenon
三重現象
growth decline
成長の衰退
increase in unemployment
失業の増加
Organizational Allocation Deterioration
組織配分の悪化
The triple phenomenon
トリプル現象
foundation eroded
基礎が侵食された
later for some reason
その後何らかの理由で
Including we have no way
仕方が無いことも含めて
Constantly providing new factors of production
常に新しい生産要素を提供する
fully employed
完全雇用
Growth-oriented developmentalism is being challenged
成長指向の開発主義が挑戦されている
Because we can't talk about everything on the spot
その場で全員で話すことはできないので、
just for economic growth
経済成長のためだけに
Too many other factors come into play
他の要因があまりにも多く影響してくる
environmental protection
環境を守ること
For example
例えば
I seem to be talking recently
最近話してる気がする
If you want to demolish a house
家を取り壊したい場合
under many conditions
多くの条件下で
to be able to look like this
このように見えることができるように
For example around here
たとえばこのあたり
Is it this ring bottle?
このリングボトルでしょうか？
of course one of them
もちろんそのうちの1人
Is there any other remedy?
他の治療法はありますか？
do you have to do this
これをしなければなりませんか
if you tear it down
それを壊したら
what might happen
何が起こるかもしれない
Zhang Jiaofang, right?
張暁芳さんですよね？
two people died, right?
2人死んだよね？
Then today you're going to demolish the house
じゃあ今日は家を取り壊すんだね
we want to dismantle the government
私たちは政府を解体したいのです
Everyone is very disgusted
みんなすごく嫌がってるよ
because you are actually developmentalist
あなたは実際に発達主義者だから
They all regard this thing as a major social loss
彼らは皆、これを大きな社会的損失だと考えている
In such a situation, it is also like this
そんな状況ではこんなこともあります
tear down the old street
古い通りを取り壊す
Because of the road, the straight road came out
道路のせいでまっすぐな道が出てきた
Then some ice pools gradually appeared, right?
すると徐々に氷だまりが現れてきますよね？
And then came the most amazing ice storage, right?
そして、最も驚くべき氷の貯蔵庫が登場しました。
He's dead against it, isn't he?
彼はそれには断固として反対していますね。
Then everyone started to sympathize with him.
それから誰もが彼に同情し始めました。
unimaginable here before
ここは以前は想像もできなかった
Of course, the situation in Taiwan is even more like this.
もちろん、台湾の状況はさらに似ています。
Continuing on independence, there is no way to maintain national security capabilities limited
独立を続けても、限られた国家安全保障能力を維持する方法はない
Or give an example, Li Hongyuan, Minister Li
あるいは例を挙げてください、李宏源、李大臣
He just kept talking
彼はただ話し続けた
You talk now and you can feel it
あなたは今話します、そしてあなたはそれを感じることができます
I know what he means
彼の言いたいことは分かる
You don't know, you don't listen to me
あなたは知らない、私の言うことを聞かない
Of course, use the stratum to go offline and then flood it.
もちろん、ストラタムを使用してオフラインにしてからフラッディングします。
Giving you 600 billion is not enough
6000億渡しても足りないよ
Just impolite and promiscuous, right?
ただ失礼で無差別なだけですよね？
that's how people are
それが人々のあり方です
New year's industrial policy in doubt
新年の産業政策に疑問が残る
In the past, the country wanted to develop
昔、国は発展したかった
Recently it seems to me
最近そう思うよ
There I saw Zhang Zhongru's impact made by a NHK Japanese
そこで私は、NHK日本人による張忠如の衝撃を見た。
I just wanted to say how did you get here on a ride?
聞きたかったんだけど、どうやって車でここまで来たの？
because of industrial policy
産業政策のせいで
It is how to bring a country in the direction of a specific industry
それは国を特定の産業の方向に導く方法です
The country is going this way
国はこの方向に進んでいる
This situation of continuing to care for is going this way
介護を続けるこの状況はこうなる
see clearly
はっきり見える
I know if it's going in any direction
何かの方向に進んでいるかどうかはわかっています
But now the industrial policy in the new field
しかし今、新たな分野における産業政策は
not so simple situation
それほど単純な状況ではない
biotechnology industry
バイオテクノロジー産業
God, how much are you going to spend in the biotech industry?
神様、バイオテクノロジー業界にいくら使うつもりですか?
How many years to burn money
お金を燃やすのに何年かかりますか
I asked a relative in America
アメリカの親戚に聞いてみた
one of his pharmaceutical factory jobs
彼の製薬工場での仕事の一つ
From the very beginning to the end of his pharmaceutical factory
彼の製薬工場の最初から最後まで
he left the drug factory
彼は製薬工場を出た
to develop a drug
薬を開発する
he made a lot of money
彼は大金を儲けた
Their medicine was never developed
彼らの薬は決して開発されなかった
I'm weird I'm thinking
私はおかしいと思っています
Will you do it alone?
一人でやりますか？
how do you get rich
どうやって金持ちになりますか
just pay yours
ただ払ってください
And how did you get so rich yourself?
そして、あなた自身はどうやってそんなに裕福になったのですか？
so you have to take a long time
だから長い時間がかかる必要がある
it is possible to create
作成することが可能です
This kind of enterprise, the products in this kind of industry
こんな企業、こんな業界の製品
Very difficult
非常に難しい
And it is still very controversial
そしてそれは今でも非常に物議を醸している
Coupled with neoliberal economic policies in power
政権の新自由主義経済政策と相まって
increase the proportion of property income
不動産収入の割合を増やす
I want to ask everyone
みんなに聞きたい
you or those around you
あなたまたはあなたの周りの人たち
How much of your money comes from new
あなたのお金のうちどれくらいが新品から来ているのか
Guys I think all the money you make is from new
皆さん、あなたが稼いだお金はすべて新しいものからだと思います
you are definitely not a rich man
あなたは間違いなく金持ちではありません
OK really rich people
OK、本当にお金持ちの人たち
his property
彼の財産
The vast majority are not from new
大部分は新品ではありません
what is it from
それは何からですか
his property
彼の財産
what is his property
彼の財産は何ですか
he is buying that house
彼はその家を買っています
He bought and sold the house
彼は家を売買した
buy again sell
また買う
how much in the middle
真ん中はいくらですか
he was in joe valley
彼はジョー・バレーにいた
He fried a big bone
彼は大きな骨を揚げた
Someone jumped in and he let go
誰かが飛び込んできて、彼は手放した
He said how much he can earn
彼はどれくらい稼げるかと言った
That's really coming and going
それは本当に行ったり来たりです
Sell ​​it compared to your whole life
あなたの人生全体と比べて売りましょう
The money to be earned will be much more
得られるお金はもっと多くなる
So do we have any restrictions on the housing market now?
では、現在住宅市場に対して何らかの制限はあるのでしょうか？
we have this market price right?
この市場価格がありますよね？
But we have announcement restrictions
ただし、発表制限があります
now want to change
今変わりたい
But the main force is very big
しかし主力は非常に大きい
and then your so-called luxury tax
それからいわゆる贅沢税
That is, you bought it and sold it quickly
つまり、買ってすぐに売ったということです
he deducts tax for you
彼はあなたのために税金を差し引いてくれる
That's what's been said recently
最近そう言われてる
Why
なぜ
young people can't stand
若者は我慢できない
Your house is hard to find.
あなたの家は見つけにくいです。
I remember that President Ma used to be like
マー総統はかつてこんな感じだったのを覚えています
Did he just come to power or when he actually got elected?
彼は権力を握ったばかりなのか、それとも実際に当選したときなのか？
I remember hearing a sentence at that time
その時に聞いた言葉を覚えています
i heard very test
とてもテストを聞いた
He said a bottle of millions is not a dream
彼は何百万ものボトルを手に入れることも夢ではないと言いました
How long will it take the young man to buy it
その若者がそれを買うのにどれくらいかかりますか
But of course, it also represents the continuous understanding of funds
しかし、もちろん、それは資金に対する継続的な理解も表しています。
full confidence in this society
この社会に対する完全な自信
So prices keep going up
だから値段が上がり続けるんだよ
So under the circumstances of Xinziroom
したがって、Xinziroom の状況では
Ami on this piece of property
この物件のアミ
as much as possible
できるだけ
Come here as much as you want
好きなだけここに来てください
Through the mechanism of the market
市場の仕組みを通じて
Buying and selling machinery wealth
機械資産の売買
The same is true for the US
米国も同様だ
The deteriorating situation of the income of the United States
米国の所得状況の悪化
compared to Taiwan
台湾と比べて
more than anything
何よりも
so these will
それで、これらは
neoliberalism is relevant
新自由主義は関係ある
Quantitative economic performance begins
定量的な経済パフォーマンスが始まる
fade
褪色
Then go to Taiwan
それから台湾に行ってください
no class conflict
階級対立はない
a very important reason
非常に重要な理由
It is our continuous high growth
それは継続的な高成長です
Rapid social mobility and extremely low unemployment
急速な社会流動性と極めて低い失業率
There is also the distribution of income relative to the military
軍関係に応じた収入の分配もある
In this case
この場合
Think about it in this high-speed flow situation
この高速の流れの状況で考えてみてください
Not easy to generate class consciousness
階級意識を生み出すのは容易ではない
right
右
But looking forward to the future we can't see
でも見えない未来を楽しみに
Prospects for improving economic conditions
経済状況の改善の見通し
So worries about economic life
だから経済生活が心配
Of course it will affect the political considerations of the people
もちろん、それは人々の政治的考慮に影響を与えるでしょう
I have no way to grow the past senior
過去の先輩を成長させる術はない
regarded as necessary
必要とみなされる
So the main axis of political competition in Taiwan
つまり、台湾における政治的競争の主軸は
Impossible not to be in this situation
この状況にならないわけがない
also affected by some
いくつかの影響も受ける
This is the economic part
これは経済的な部分です
Let's talk about a kind of mobilization
一種の動員について話しましょう
the exhaustion
疲労感
It's been robbed
盗まれてしまった
already tired
もう疲れた
When the public is still accustomed to accepting
大衆がまだ受け入れることに慣れているとき
When seen as a major social divide
大きな社会的格差とみなされる場合
economic factors at that time
その時の経済的要因
still no way to become a voter
まだ有権者になる方法はない
I think this is the primary consideration
これが主な考慮事項だと思います
let me give you an example
例をあげましょう
in 2001
2001年に
Taiwan has experienced unprecedented secondary growth
台湾は前例のない第二次成長を遂げた
previous oil crises
以前の石油危機
We don't have secondary growth
二次成長はありません
Back then it was vice 1.65
当時はバイス1.65でした
Income distribution is deteriorating rapidly
所得分配は急速に悪化している
At that time, the Kuomintang jumped out and said
その時、国民党が飛び出してきてこう言いました。
Wow look what the economy is doing
うわー、経済がどうなっているのか見てみましょう
Attacking the Democratic Progressive Party like this
民進党をこう攻撃する
But voters were not affected by this
しかし、有権者はこれに影響されませんでした
Basically in 2004 we had a presidential election
基本的に2004年に大統領選挙がありました
March and congressional elections in December
3月と12月に議会選挙
maintain the political status quo
政治的現状を維持する
This is really the status of the Democratic Progressive Party
これが民進党の実態だ
Nor was it affected by today's performance
今日のパフォーマンスの影響も受けなかった
why is this very important
なぜこれがとても重要なのでしょうか
Because Taiwan's economy has been growing rapidly in the past
台湾は過去に急速な経済成長を遂げてきましたので、
At that time there was an unprecedented major crisis
当時は未曾有の大危機に見舞われていた
But the common people have no rules and the ruling party
しかし庶民にはルールも与党もない
In the era of Ah Bian
阿ビアンの時代
Almost Every Election Becomes a Consensus Choice
ほぼすべての選挙はコンセンサスによる選択となる
Even when the Democratic Progressive Party's election situation began to decline in 2005
2005年に民進党の選挙情勢が低迷し始めたときでさえ
President Chen still insists on confronting the KMT on the issues he agrees with
陳総統は依然として、自分が同意する問題について国民党と対決することを主張している
Let's take a look at the main picture in the previous paragraph
前の段落のメイン画像を見てみましょう
Too much of this event revolves around periods of identification
この出来事の多くは、特定の期間を中心に展開しています
It was the big thing at that time
当時はそれが大事件だった
Now we talk about the big trend and the big wrong has its special meaning
ここで私たちは大きなトレンドについて話します、そして大きな間違いには特別な意味があります
right
右
But at that time the tide
でもその時の潮流は
astaffy is there
アスタフィーはそこにいる
There are two levels of antagonism in society
社会には2つのレベルの対立がある
Of course many people think
もちろんそう思う人も多いだろう
this time can't stand
今回は耐えられない
can you stop doing this
これをやめてもらえますか
And cross-strait relations
そして海峡を越えた関係
And the relationship between Taiwan and the United States
そして台湾とアメリカの関係
also under tension
それも緊張状態で
of course it looks like this
もちろんこう見えます
So recognize the cost of mobilization
したがって、動員のコストを認識する
looks full height
全高に見える
Okay, I'm going to talk about the third factor now.
さて、ここからは 3 番目の要素について話します。
Cause our axis may transform
だって私たちの軸は変わるかもしれないから
On the one hand you care about the economy
一方で、あなたは経済を気にします
I think this is the most important thing
これが最も重要なことだと思います
On the other hand, I agree that there are too many mobilizations
一方で、動員が多すぎるという意見にも同意します
also feel tired
疲れも感じます
Between these two there is actually one more
この 2 つの間に、実はもう 1 つあります
This link is cross-strait relations
このリンクは海峡を越えた関係です
This was in 2008
これは2008年のことでした
A Logical Deduction of the KMT
国民党の論理的演繹
how does it say
それはどのように言いますか
Taiwan's economy is slowing down
台湾経済は減速している
Distribution becomes an important issue
配布が重要な課題になる
At that time, I was talking all day long
あの時は一日中喋ってた
How many people died by burning charcoal
炭を燃やして何人死んだか
how many people committed suicide or what
何人が自殺したのか、それとも
Now the DPP is saying the same thing about the KMT
今、民進党も国民党に対して同じことを言っている
But it was the KMT who started talking about it
しかし、それについて話し始めたのは国民党でした
Let's just say the economy is getting worse.
経済が悪化しているとだけ言っておきましょう。
Everyone feels that it is
誰もがそうだと感じている
An important reason for Taiwan's economic growth
台湾の経済成長の重要な理由
is tense to cross-strait relations
海峡を越えた関係に緊張している
Because the relationship between the two sides was really tense at that time.
当時、両国の関係は非常に緊張していたからです。
Is investment can not improve
投資では改善できないのか
if you want to invest
投資したいなら
Will you put the money on the missile
ミサイルにお金をかけてくれませんか
over there
そちら側
Or the side where the missiles are going to go down?
それともミサイルが落ちてくる側でしょうか？
So Shanghai has a lot of investment
上海には多額の投資がある
But you want to invest in Taiwan
しかし、あなたは台湾に投資したいと考えています
Wealthy people ask for money
裕福な人はお金を要求する
Of course I want a political stability
もちろん政治的安定は望むが
One kind of public opinion is yellow hole
世論の一種はイエローホールです
so you want to improve the economy
それで経済を改善したいのですか
You need to improve cross-strait relations
両岸関係を改善する必要がある
I can't fight that bowl like it's going to war
あのボウルと戦争するかのように戦うことはできない
To improve cross-strait relations
両岸関係の改善に向けて
From your external standpoint
外部の立場から見ると
A certain form of One China must come out
ある形の「一つの中国」が出てくるはずだ
it's a hollow thought
それは空虚な考えだ
how is a
はどうですか
We have said in the past they can accept
私たちは過去に、彼らは受け入れることができると言いました
so
それで
If you want something like this
このようなものが欲しい場合は
The so-called Chinese things come out
いわゆる中華物が出てきます
Nature can't be very strong
自然はそれほど強いものではない
anthropogenic awareness
人土意識
For example, you can't
たとえば、次のことはできません。
On the one hand there is on the other hand too much to see
一方で、見るべきものが多すぎる
So the 1992 Consensus reappeared
そこで1992年のコンセンサスが再び登場した
The 1992 Consensus is a term that Su Qi came up with
1992年コンセンサスはスー・チーが考え出した用語である
In fact, there was no such term before
実際、以前はそのような用語はありませんでした
So Lee Teng-hui scolded him
そこで李登輝は叱った。
i want to die
私は死にたい
Everyone is serious, in fact, he thinks
みんな真剣だ、実は彼はこう思っている
he is right
彼は正しい
But he did come down to it
しかし、彼はそれに到達した
A so-called consensus at that time
いわゆる当時のコンセンサス
What consensus? It's actually very simple
コンセンサスは何ですか? それは実際には非常に簡単です
On one side is the People's Republic of China
一方には中華人民共和国があります
On one side is the Republic of China
一方には中華民国がある
the republic of china says
中華民国は言う
no republic of china
中華民国はない
The mainland belongs to the Republic of China
本土は中華民国に属します
The People's Republic of China does not have the Republic of China
中華人民共和国には中華民国はない
It has also become the 26th or 27th century
それも26世紀か27世紀になった
is it? ok
大丈夫ですか
That Taiwan belongs to China
台湾は中国に属する
Both the south side and the north side stand
南側と北側の両方が立っています
How do you come up with something in common?
どうやって共通点を思いつきますか？
is what we think of in common
私たちが共通して考えていることは
what have in common
共通点は何ですか
Everyone thinks I only have one China
誰もが私には中国が一つしかないと思っている
so
それで
that's right
それは正しい
in this case
この場合
The 1992 consensus cannot be stopped
1992年のコンセンサスは止められない
But this horse is also interesting
でもこの馬も面白いですよ
He was actually in the 1980s
彼は実際には1980年代にいた
out that time
その時間外に
He's in Luyouhui
彼は洛陽匯にいるよ
he imagined
彼は想像した
Good God, I always figured it out at that time
ああ、あの時はいつも分かっていたんだ
There is this so-called 9 case
いわゆる9ケースというのがあります。
At that time, it was not called Case 9.
当時はケース9とは呼ばれていませんでした。
Consensus submission of each table
各テーブルの合意提出
come out and write his name
出てきて彼の名前を書いてください
one table
1つのテーブル
That's how I thought about it at that time
その時はそう思った
But time has changed so long
しかし、時代は大きく変わりました
By the year 2000
2000年までに
Taiwanese society is no longer the same
台湾社会はもはや以前と同じではない
you speak a variety of words
あなたは色々な言葉を話します
Some people may not accept
受け付けない人もいるかもしれない
so he said
それで彼は言いました
This consensus in 1992
1992 年のこのコンセンサス
one table
1つのテーブル
Let's call it the 9-case consensus
私たちはそれを9ケースコンセンサスと呼んでいます
Then what
じゃあ何
I talk about the consensus of 9 cases
9件の総意についてお話します
What about the mainland?
本土はどうですか？
As long as there is a consensus on the 9 cases, there will be no war
9件の事件で合意がある限り、戦争は起こらない
As long as you talk about the consensus of 9 cases, you can have investment
9件の合意を踏まえて話し合えば投資可能
Just talk about the consensus of 9 cases
9件の合意について話してください
the economy will get better
経済は良くなるだろう
He just said yes
彼はただ「はい」と言いました
just say yes
はいと言って
Because the 9-case consensus did not say
9件の合意ではこうは言っていなかったので
This is one table
これは 1 つのテーブルです
Because people in Taiwan listen to the mainland a lot
台湾の人は大陸の曲をよく聞くから
He has a natural resentment
彼は生まれつきの憤りを持っている
Just jump up when you hear one
音が聞こえたら飛び上がってください
But what if you say
しかし、あなたが言ったらどうしますか
The One China we talk about is the 1992 Consensus
私たちが語る「一つの中国」とは1992年のコンセンサスです
Then as long as you hear that one in two is talking about the 1992 Consensus
では、2人に1人が1992年コンセンサスについて話していると聞く限り、
The 1992 consensus is so good
1992年のコンセンサスは非常に優れている
when you feel good
気分が良いとき
President Ma said that when
馬総統はその時こう言った。
Dr. Ma Presidential Candidate Says Again
マー博士、大統領候補が改めて語る
my eyes are ready
私の目の準備はできています
Do you remember the galloping horse
疾走する馬を覚えていますか
Every county magistrate comes out and says it's ready
すべての郡判事が出てきて、準備はできていると言う
Ready
準備
make a big impact
大きな影響を与える
At that time, the DPP had a lot of corruption, what?
当時、民進党は汚職が多かった、あれ？
Ah Bian, the people below are going to gamble again.
ああ、ビアン、下の人々はまたギャンブルをするつもりです。
His wife is counting that again
彼の妻はまたそれを数えています
what is this receipt
この領収書は何ですか
therefore
したがって
In order to revitalize Taiwan's economy, we must stop agreeing with the mobilization
台湾経済を活性化するためには、動員への同意をやめなければなりません。
Then
それから
Economic recovery and identity are upside down
経済回復とアイデンティティはひっくり返る
If you want to do a good job in the economy, you should stop doing that thing.
経済で良い仕事をしたいなら、そんなことはやめるべきだ。
And in Taiwan at that time
そして当時の台湾では
is audible
聞こえる
So the economic power of the electorate demands to be acquainted with the initiative for Taiwan's indigenous identity
したがって、有権者の経済力は、台湾の先住民族のアイデンティティに対する取り組みを知ることを要求している
But let's not talk about this yet
でも、これについてはまだ話さないでおこう
The economy is so bad right now
今、景気がすごく悪いので、
that's better
その方が良いです
Such logic can gain the support of many voters
このような論理は多くの有権者の支持を得ることができる
Overall economic downturn
全体的な景気低迷
identification mobilization boredom
識別動員の退屈
The cross-strait relations I just talked about
先ほど話した両岸関係
The link between identity and economics
アイデンティティと経済のつながり
One is that we are worried when the economy goes down
一つは、景気が悪くなると不安になるということ
One is that we can't stand the identification for too long
1つは、あまりにも長い時間の同一化に耐えられないということ
One is that I want to boost the economy
一つは経済を活性化させたいということ
It is necessary to improve cross-strait relations
両岸関係を改善する必要がある
improve cross-strait relations
両岸関係を改善する
to accept a certain degree of one-China principle
ある程度の「一つの中国」原則を受け入れる
To do so, one must accept the 1992 Consensus
そうするためには、1992年のコンセンサスを受け入れる必要があります
And you are going to talk about the 1992 Consensus
そしてあなたは 1992 年のコンセンサスについて話そうとしています
Of course you can't be high
もちろんハイになることはできません
your Taiwan independence identity
あなたの台湾独立のアイデンティティ
so there is an instrumental link between the two
したがって、両者の間には手段的なつながりがあります
These three factors combined
これら 3 つの要素が組み合わさって
You will find that the axis starts to shift
軸がずれ始めていることがわかります
First the KMT then the DPP
まずは国民党、次に民進党
from our point of view
私たちの観点からすると
When the KMT does this
国民党がこれをやると
In fact, it has also gone through a process
実はこれもプロセスを経ています
In the mid-1990s the concept of China
1990年代半ばには中国という概念が
increasingly politicized
ますます政治化
And it became specific to mainland China
そしてそれは中国本土特有のものとなった
I used to grow up in our time
私たちの時代には成長していました
it doesn't feel like that
そんな感じではない
But it's getting more and more like this
でも、どんどんこうなってきてるよ
So Chinese identity in Taiwan
台湾における中国人のアイデンティティ
gradually dissolve
徐々に溶ける
Chinese nationalism
中国のナショナリズム
it seems untenable
それは耐えられないようです
The Democratic Progressive Party in this era of identity change
アイデンティティ変革の時代における民進党
Rise into great political gain
大きな政治的利益を得る
But the KMT retreated all the way
しかし国民党は全面撤退した
and it gradually takes a
そしてそれは徐々に時間がかかります
Vague and Fluid Position
曖昧で流動的な位置
how does it say
それはどのように言いますか
it first declares itself
最初にそれ自体を宣言します
Even if China is Taiwan
たとえ中国が台湾であっても
So come up with it and call it
それで思いついて呼んでみてください
Republic of China in Taiwan
台湾における中華民国
both have
両方持っています
And gradually increase the proportion of the second identity
そして徐々に第二のアイデンティティの割合を増やしていきます
accent on the second scale
第2スケールのアクセント
When the Kuomintang was in the presidential university in 2000
2000年に国民党が総統大学にいた頃
After Lee Teng-hui was defeated and transferred to the green camp
李登輝が敗れて緑陣営に移送された後
The traditional position of the Kuomintang
国民党の伝統的な立場
Looks like there's no way to maintain
維持する方法がないようです
At least those in the KMT
少なくとも国民党の人々は
think so
そう思う
So the KMT
それで国民党は
fall into opposition position
反対の立場に陥る
he lost the first time
彼は初めて負けた
he is thinking
彼は考えています
Of course less talk about recognition
もちろん、認識についての話は少なくなります
Now the government is the Democratic Progressive Party
現在の政権は民進党です
while the Democratic Progressive Party
一方、民進党は
The economy has deteriorated
景気が悪化した
Of course, they desperately attacked the Democratic Progressive Party.
もちろん彼らは民進党を必死に攻撃した。
There is no way to properly handle Taiwan's economic crisis
台湾の経済危機に適切に対処する方法はない
His transformation was natural
彼の変化は自然だった
The KMT began to enter by identifying with
と同一化して国民党が参入し始めた。
transition to economy
経済への移行
1990 2,000
1990年2,000年
In 2005, after entering and leaving the chairman of the Kuomintang party
2005年、国民党主席への入退任を経て
He began to downplay the identity controversy
彼はアイデンティティ論争を軽視し始めた
what did he say
彼が何を言ったの
He said drug evasion was a legal option
彼は麻薬から逃れることは合法的な選択肢だと述べた
KMT on February 14, 2006
国民党、2006 年 2 月 14 日
published in the Liberty Times
リバティタイムズに掲載されました
Advertising in the age of modernization
近代化時代の広告
he said so
彼はそう言いました
He keeps talking about political unity
彼は政治的統一について話し続けている
I said Ah Bian scolded me to death, right?
ア・ビアンに死ぬほど叱られたって言ったよね？
next time
次の時間
He never talked about it again
彼はそのことについて二度と話しませんでした
Automatically unification
自動的に統合
so
それで
Made strategy ahead of presidential election
大統領選挙を前に戦略を立てる
take a step back
下がってください
Then act for the Democratic Progressive Party
その後民進党で活動する
stop talking about this
このことについて話すのはやめてください
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
that's the ad
それが広告です
liberty times
空き時間
In February 2000, the interesting thing is that these Liberty Times lamps
2000 年 2 月、興味深いのは、これらのリバティ タイムズ ランプが
how on earth is this written
いったいこれはどうやって書かれているのか
The Chinese Nationalist Party advocates competition in the spirit of democracy
中国国民党は民主主義の精神に基づく競争を提唱
Taiwan has many possible options for the future
台湾には将来に向けて多くの選択肢がある
Whether it is the same independence or the maintenance of the status quo
同じ独立か現状維持か
must be decided by the people
国民が決めなければならない
The Kuomintang's claim
国民党の主張
say you want to ask me
私に聞きたいと言ってください
Although all three
3つともですが、
you ask me
あなたは私に尋ねます
Taiwan should maintain the status quo of the ROC
台湾は中華民国の現状を維持すべきだ
Circle it like this, right?
このように丸で囲んでくださいね？
but one thing to note
ただし、注意すべきことが1つあります
How about his whole discourse?
彼の談話全体についてはどうでしょうか？
to transform the Republic of China from a supreme constitutional and moral obligation
中華民国を最高の憲法的および道徳的義務から転換する
This used to be in this part of the KMT
ここはかつて国民党のこの部分にあった
there is no need to discuss
議論する必要はない
It has become a political proposition chosen by the public voters
それは国民の有権者によって選ばれた政治的命題となった
it makes a big difference
それは大きな違いを生みます
It used to say you had to be loyal to the constitution
昔は憲法に忠実でなければならないと言われていました
than traditionally there is such a legitimacy
伝統的にそのような正当性があるよりも
With this tradition is the Republic of China
この伝統を持つのが中華民国です
The founding father of the Republic of China cannot be relied on
中華民国の建国の父は頼りにならない
what are you talking about
あなたは何について話していますか
So call Han the Republic of China
だからハンを中華民国と呼ぶ
What is Ma Britain's law now?
マ・ブリテン法は今どうなっているのか？
Oh, you talk about independence
ああ、あなたは独立について話しています
Someone said unity
誰かが団結って言った
In fact, he didn't say that before, he didn't say that
実際、彼は前にもそんなこと言ってなかったし、そんなことも言ってなかった
Some people say that maintaining the status quo is me
現状維持が私だという人もいる
Then he does a poll and finds that the status quo is the most
それから彼は世論調査を行ったところ、現状維持が最も多いことがわかりました。
That means I'm arguing for the status quo
つまり現状維持を主張しているということだ
I don't object to you either. What about your method?
私もあなたに反対はしませんが、あなたのやり方はどうですか？
also has his reason
彼の理由もあります
It's okay if everyone likes him
みんなが彼を好きならそれでいいよ
But mine is better
でも私のほうがいいよ
He turns himself into an option, a commodity in the middle of the political market
彼は自分自身を政治市場の真ん中でオプション、商品に変える
Let everyone be free to decide
みんなに自由に決めてもらいましょう
Rather than saying that under the norms of the law
法律の規範の下でそう言うのではなく
must
しなければならない
The moral, obligatory, supreme thing
道徳的で義務的で最高のもの
I used to look at it like this
よくこんな感じで見ていました
So in the process the horse has turned
その過程で馬は向きを変えた
Since 2006
2006年開始
KMT Freezes Identity Controversy
国民党、アイデンティティ論争を凍結
emphasize
強調
economic importance
経済的重要性
Then to ease cross-strait relations
それなら海峡両岸関係を緩和する必要がある
That's why Xiao Wanqiang's cross-strait common market emerged.
だからこそ、蕭万強の両岸共同市場が登場したのである。
The 1992 Consensus with Su Qi became the main axis of the campaign
スー・チーとの1992年のコンセンサスがキャンペーンの主軸となった
Cross-strait relations are understood in terms of economic interests
両岸関係は経済的利益の観点から理解される
Utilize civil for economical transactions
民事を経済的な取引に活用する
Improve relations between the Kuomintang and the other side
国民党と相手側との関係改善
provide a basis for public opinion
世論の根拠を提供する
In the KMT election campaign
国民党の選挙活動において
economy is the main purpose
経済が主な目的です
Cross-strait relations are tools for promotion
両岸関係は促進のためのツールである
Freezing identity disputes is a necessary means to improve cross-strait relations
アイデンティティ紛争の凍結は両岸関係を改善するために必要な手段である
Such a logical layout
このような論理的なレイアウト
It hasn't changed until today
それは今日まで変わっていない
so it's realistic
だからそれは現実的です
instrumental discourse
器楽的談話
Quite different from the claims of instrumental ideology
道具的イデオロギーの主張とはまったく異なる
The Democratic Party is totally different
民主党は全然違う
KMT challenge Naro Narok refuses to give up at first
国民党、ナロに挑戦 ナロは最初は諦めなかった
Looks like a strong battlefield
強力な戦場のようです
Still put forward various proposals on the identity
アイデンティティに関しては現在もさまざまな提案を行っている
I remember that time
あの時のことを覚えています
Even the electricity bill supports IoT
電気代もIoT対応
put a lot of things on it
その上にたくさんの物を置きます
Roll the head into the face, the body is fresh, etc.
頭を顔に押し付けると、体はフレッシュになります。
So you found a very interesting thing today
さて、今日はとても興味深いものを見つけましたね
What about blue and green? Blue fights blue, not green fights green.
青と緑はどうでしょうか? 青は青と戦いますが、緑が緑と戦うのではありません。
The blue is not the green is talking about the classics
青は緑ではない、古典について話している
Green always speaks, agrees, agrees, agrees
グリーンはいつも話し、同意、同意、同意
So the competition between these two becomes
したがって、これら 2 つの間の競争は、
It's not just a competition between blue and green
単なる青と緑の競争ではない
It's a competition between two different issues
それは 2 つの異なる問題間の競争です
In 2008, of course, there were various factors
2008年には、もちろんさまざまな要因がありました
but no matter
でも関係ない
The two generations of Mingyue, the Congress and their classmates, will lose in both
ミンゲの二世代、議会とその同級生たちはどちらの戦でも負けることになるだろう。
This number is very large compared with before
この数字は以前と比べて非常に大きいです
The numbers fifteen percent and seventeen percent
15パーセントと17パーセントという数字
Then tomorrow, the review will start.
そして明日から審査が始まります。
Then in his mind, in fact, Tsai Ing-wen
そして彼の心の中では、実は蔡英文さんは
Tsai Ing-wen is not the leader of any faction
蔡英文氏はどの派閥の指導者でもない
Tsai Ing-wen, our understanding is basically
蔡英文さん、私たちの理解は基本的には
Lee Teng-hui suggested to Chen Shui-bian
李登輝が陳水扁に提案
And he just happens not to be from any faction
そして彼はたまたまどの派閥にも属していないだけです
So he became the new chairman of the party
それで彼は党の新しい議長になった
under his agency to begin the transformation
彼の代理の下で変革を始める
So the transformation of the Kuomintang and the transformation of the DPP
国民党の変革と民進党の変革
all because
すべての理由
Because of electing the DPP after 2008
2008年以降に民進党に当選したため
Editorial Benefits of Any Same Momentum
同じ勢いによる編集上の利点
Doesn't it look tall?
背が高く見えませんか？
That just so happens that he's in the opposition now.
たまたま彼は今野党にいるんだ。
The KMT is the ruling party
国民党は与党です
So the KMT's economic performance is very convenient
つまり国民党の経済パフォーマンスは非常に都合が良いのです
To evaluate the target, APPFIRE, house price,
ターゲット、APPFIRE、住宅価格を評価するには、
The unemployed under this huge height
この巨大な高さの下で失業者
In fact, the government at the time of the 2012 case
実際、2012 年の事件当時、政府は
I want to give this young man who has just come out of work
仕事を終えたばかりのこの若者に贈りたい
a concession
譲歩
Pay attention to the lights
ライトに注意してください
he gave him 2012
他給他2012
Because you probably didn't have a job at all.
なぜなら、あなたにはおそらく仕事がなかったからです。
So the government pays some money
それで政府はお金を出します
Then these companies will use 22K
そうすれば、これらの企業は 22K を使用することになります
Then look after this young man
それならこの若者の世話をしてください
As everyone knows, more companies are on the same page
誰もが知っているように、より多くの企業が同じ考えを持っています
So your original 24K also jump to 22K
したがって、元の 24K も 22K にジャンプします。
so i complained so much
だから私はたくさん文句を言いました
policies like this
このような政策
Of course there are places to attack
もちろん攻める場所もある
so in a sense
だからある意味では
Tsai Ing-wen took the route of Ma Ying-jeou
蔡英文氏は馬英九氏の道を歩んだ
how to say
どのように言って
In his mind, he leaned towards the middle
心の中で彼は真ん中に傾いていた
Let's think about Tsai Ing-wen
蔡英文さんについて考えてみましょう
We'll have a picture of him in our minds.
私たちの心の中には彼の姿が浮かぶでしょう。
his speech
彼のスピーチ
Then think about Chen Shui-bian
それなら陳水扁のことを考えてください
then he looks like
それから彼は次のように見えます
his speech
彼のスピーチ
can you feel it
感じるかい
The two of them seem to be from different planets
二人は違う星から来たようだ
very big difference
非常に大きな違い
he is alone
彼は一人です
year before running for president
大統領に立候補する1年前
This sentence was spoken on the Double Tenth National Day in 2011
この文は 2011 年の建国記念日の二重十日に語られたものです
The Republic of China is Taiwan
中華民国は台湾です
But the meaning of this is actually what the Democratic Progressive Party has said
しかし、この意味は実は民進党が言っていることなのです
But what he means by this is
しかし、彼がこれで言いたいのは、
you do not need to worry
心配する必要はありません
if i come up
私が来たら
I will not take away the four characters of the Republic of China
中華民国の四文字は奪わない
Many people for the Republic of China
中華民国を支持する多くの人々
is a note with a strong emotion
強い感情を込めたメモです
It means to go in the middle
真ん中に行くという意味です
realistic
現実的な
His objection to APP
APPに対する彼の反対
A realistic economic standpoint
現実的な経済的観点
I remember that there are many advertisements of the Democratic Progressive Party
民進党の広告が多かった記憶がある
like chamon et al
シャモンらのように
that is
あれは
If that EKFA comes
あのEKFAが来たら
their livelihoods are affected
彼らの生活は影響を受ける
he does not use ideological methods
彼はイデオロギー的な手法を使用しません
come against him
彼に立ち向かう
what he said was very realistic
彼の言ったことはとても現実的だった
Tsai Ying-ming wants to organize Taiwan independence
蔡英明氏は台湾独立を組織したいと考えている
Cai Yingming has a group Zhang Gong to join the alliance
蔡英明は張公を同盟に参加させる
Cai Yingming has a group certificate
蔡英明は団体証明書を持っています
Tsai Ying-ming organized Zhang to make a constitution
蔡英明は張氏を組織して憲法を制定させた
These group sheets from the A-bian era
Aビアン時代のグループシート
Cai does not speak at all
蔡さんは全く喋らない
Therefore, the Democratic Progressive Party has gradually shifted from political to economic
このため、民進党は徐々に政治から経済へ移行してきました。
Also Freeze Policy
政策も凍結する
Economy hangs over overall median voter appointments
経済は有権者任命の全体の中央値に影響を及ぼしている
but please when you go like this
でも、このように行くときはお願いします
when you walk like this
こうやって歩くと
What do you say about your life voters
あなたの人生の有権者について何と言いますか
don't be afraid
恐れないでください
He has no one but you to vote for
彼にはあなた以外に投票できる人がいません
Which one do you ask him to vote for?
あなたは彼にどちらに投票するよう頼みますか?
In Namadang History Network, a Relying on People Versus Producing Voters
ナマダン歴史ネットワークでは、人に依存するか、有権者を生み出すか
also the same
また同じです
so
それで
This is the KMT's 2008 set of strategies
これは国民党の 2008 年の一連の戦略です
Two middle walks happened
2つの中四球が発生しました
result
結果
We have seen the DPP win for a decade
私たちは民進党が10年間勝利するのを見てきた
A series of by-elections whose support is now picking up
支持が高まっている一連の補欠選挙
In the 5th election in 2010, the total number of votes exceeded the KMT
2010年の第5回選挙では得票総数が国民党を上回った
5% if you add up the county and city elections in the previous year
前年の郡選挙と市選挙を合計すると 5%
You will find that the DPP has more votes than the KMT
民進党の方が国民党よりも多くの票を持っていることがわかります。
Although the DPP did not win back power in 2012
民進党は2012年に政権を取り戻すことはできなかったが、
But has significantly reduced the gap between the KMT
しかし国民党との溝は大幅に縮まった
Congress is from 15 to 10 presidents, and from 17% to 6%
議会の大統領は15人から10人、支持率は17％から6％
i remember before that presidential election
あの大統領選挙前のことを覚えている
There are many predictions that Tsai Ing-wen may win
蔡英文さんが勝つという予想が多い
let you think about the situation at that time
その時の状況を考えてみましょう
Then she campaigned with her personal image, and her demands are far from the candidates of the Democratic Progressive Party in the past.
その後、彼女は個人的なイメージを掲げて選挙活動を行ったが、彼女の要求は過去の民進党候補者の要求とはかけ離れている。
But some people like to hear it so much
しかし、それをとても聞くのが好きな人もいます
But in fact she is quite similar to Ma Ying-jeou
しかし実際には彼女は馬英九によく似ている
isn't it
ではない？
Received this education abroad
海外でこの教育を受けた
She can't even speak Taiwanese correctly.
彼女は台湾語さえ正確に話せません。
her english is very good
彼女の英語はとても上手です
It's cold when she talks
彼女が話すと寒い
not easy to explain
説明するのは簡単ではない
man ji ang this
マン・ジアン、これ
that stirs up
それは興奮する
I remember the night before the election
選挙前夜のことを覚えている
You go back and bless him
あなたは戻って彼を祝福します
But when he's most emotional
でも彼が一番感情的になったとき
It seems that you keep Taiwan's secrets
台湾の秘密を守っているようですね
Give Tsai Ing-wen
蔡英文さんにあげよ
That person changed and said your action
あの人は変わってあなたの行動を言いました
not cai herself
蔡本人ではない
Tsai Ing-wen is not that kind of horse
蔡英文はそんな馬ではない
Ji Ang's that can agitate
興奮できるジアン
this
これ
just when you were there
ちょうどあなたがそこにいたとき
Hello everyone
こんにちは、みんな
call it this way
このように呼んでください
Then there are some gestures
それからいくつかのジェスチャーがあります
It feels like there is no way to be brought up by him.
彼に育てられても仕方がないような気がする。
These two are actually
実はこの二人は
in the colder
寒い中で
such a presidential candidate
そんな大統領候補
the leader
リーダー
so interesting
興味深い
So we see that the KMT and the DPP
したがって、国民党と民進党は
learn from each other
お互いから学び合う
And learn from the lessons of defeat
そして敗北の教訓から学びましょう
KMT downplays his Chinese nationalism
国民党は中国ナショナリズムを軽視する
adopt a hybrid identity
ハイブリッドアイデンティティを採用する
then turn to economics
それから経済学に目を向ける
Any mobilization and acceptance of economic
あらゆる経済活動の動員と受け入れ
as the main topic
メイントピックとして
Both parties learn from defeat
双方とも敗北から学んでいる
magan vegetables to a considerable extent
かなりの量のマガン野菜
converted their political parties
彼らの政党を改宗させた
However, we have to ask the transformation
しかし、私たちは変革を問う必要があります。
Is it decisive
決定的ですか
And what might happen in the future
そして将来何が起こるかもしれない
then continue to look down
それからずっと下を見続ける
there are three words
言葉が3つあります
One is replacement
一つは交換です
one is crisscrossing
1つは交差しています
one is facade
一つはファサード
That replacement is to replace
その代替品は代替品です
Is it possible for the economy to actually replace
実際に経済が代替する可能性はあるのか
Has identity become the main axis of political competition in Taiwan?
台湾ではアイデンティティが政治競争の主軸になっているのでしょうか？
if it is like this
このような場合
is to identify the relevant issues
関連する問題を特定することです
no longer the main axis
もはや主軸ではない
The economy becomes the core issue
経済が中心問題になる
Here I have three
ここに3つあります
This shade of development
この発展の色合い
One is the economic vote
一つは経済投票です
economic vote
経済投票
Those who engage in economic voting are small
経済投票に参加する人は少数である
There are some fine distinctions in it
細かい区別がいくつかあります
Forward-looking is his retrospective is his society is his personal
前向きとは彼の回想であり、彼の社会は彼の個人的なものである
basically means
基本的に意味するのは
Are you looking at the present or the future?
あなたは現在を見ていますか、それとも未来を見ていますか？
Or you look at your pocket
あるいはポケットを見ると
Or look at the whole society
あるいは社会全体を見てみると
Anyway, he just depends on the overall economic situation to decide.
いずれにせよ、彼は全体的な経済状況に応じて決定するだけです。
is it how to vote
投票の仕方ですか
completely determined by the economy
完全に経済によって決まる
The second one I call distributive politics
2つ目は私が分配政治と呼ぶものです
That is to say, the two parties
つまり、両者は、
It will combine with various interest groups
さまざまな利益団体と結合するだろう
When you vote, it depends on which interest group you belong to
投票するときは、どの利益団体に属しているかによって決まります
Which party to vote for
どの政党に投票するか
As is often the case in the United States,
アメリカではよくあることですが、
In Europe it is often the case that
ヨーロッパではよくあることですが、
class vote
階級投票
Then I'd say I'm a Labor family
だったら私は労働党の家族だと言うだろう
I have always been a laborer
私はずっと労働者でした
Then I have been a laborer for many generations
それから私は何世代にもわたって労働者でした
and then myself
それから私自身
So I'm full of this class history
だから私はこのクラスの履歴でいっぱいです
Then I will definitely work
それなら絶対に働きます
no problem anyway
とにかく問題ない
no matter what
何があっても
It's all a form of substituting economics for identity
それはすべて、アイデンティティを経済学に置き換える一種です
We found that if we do
そうすれば、
then social divisions are unprecedented
そうすれば社会の分断は前例のないものになる
turned the matter
問題を変えた
KMT may transform into a center-right party
国民党は中道右派政党に変貌する可能性がある
The DPP may become a center-left party
民進党は中道左派政党になるかもしれない
if he doesn't
彼がそうしないなら
may have to this class
このクラスに行かなければならないかもしれません
Left and right oriented parties will replace them
左派と右派の政党が彼らに取って代わるだろう
Normalization of Taiwan politics
台湾政治の正常化
We take left and right as the main axis of competition
左右を競争の主軸とする
looks like western
西洋っぽい
but of course
しかし、もちろん
Of course, it is impossible to completely eliminate the love house that I agree with.
もちろん、私が同意するラブハウスを完全に排除することは不可能です。
It is difficult to hide the factors of mainland China
中国本土の要因を隠すのは難しい
who knows what will happen to them
彼らに何が起こるか誰にも分からない
so of course we know
もちろん私たちは知っています
This identity politics is likely to be faked again
このアイデンティティ政治はまた捏造される可能性が高い
Basically, as long as there is no that, it will slowly replace
基本的に、それがない限り、ゆっくりと置き換えられます
this is the first possibility
これが最初の可能性です
The second possibility is that the appearance is a Façade
2 番目の可能性は、外観がファサードであることです。
What does that mean
どういう意味ですか
The economy is just a mask for deep identities
経済は深いアイデンティティを隠す仮面にすぎない
Economists on both sides of the strait supported by the Kuomintang and the Kuomintang
国民党と海峡両岸の経済学者が支持
Not because they want to revive Taiwan's economy
台湾経済を活性化したいからではない
But because it still has a unified love house inside
でも中にはまだ統一されたラブハウスがあるから
DPP opposes cross-strait economic integration
民進党は両岸経済統合に反対
Not because of any economic and practical factors
経済的および現実的な要因によるものではありません
It is because its deep concept is to legalize Taiwan independence.
それは台湾独立を合法化するという深い構想があるからである。
So it is the enemy division for mainland China
つまり中国本土にとっては敵師団である
The economic language and rational thinking used by both sides
双方が使用する経済用語と合理的思考
It's all fake appearances
それはすべて偽りの姿です
truly influential
本当に影響力のある
It is the deep recognition of the two parties and the two camps
それは両党、両陣営の深い認識である
copy the language of the economy
経済の言葉をコピーする
identity
身元
Sensibility actually surpasses rationality
感性は実は理性を超える
is that so
そうですか
if legal
合法であれば
not only political parties hypocrisy
偽善政党だけではない
voters are hypocritical
有権者は偽善的だ
Voters seem to accept rational economic discourse
有権者は合理的な経済議論を受け入れているようだ
In fact it accepts a bipartisan message
実際、超党派のメッセージを受け入れています
emotion of identification
同一化の感情
if it's not about you talking
あなたが話していることではないなら
How much
いくら
How many percentage points does the unemployment rate increase?
失業率は何パーセント上昇しますか?
I hear what you think makes sense or doesn't make sense
意味があると思うか、意味がないと思うか聞いています
not by the soundness of your economic argument
あなたの経済的議論の健全さによるものではない
to decide
決定する
but your statement
しかしあなたの発言
Identify with the one hidden deep within me
自分の奥深くに隠れているものと同一化する
Can it be hooked together?
一緒に引っ掛けることはできますか？
If I think I can hook it up
繋げられると思ったら
if i were blue i would say
もし私が青だったらこう言うだろう
then i listen to you
聞きます
The mainland has good development opportunities
本土には良い発展の機会がある
why i go
なぜ私が行くのか
makes sense
意味がある
If it's beneficial, I'll think of it
有益なら考えます
Oh no
なんてこった
Taiwan is doomed
台湾は滅亡する運命にある
The service industry is dying
サービス業は滅びつつある
All the electricity will go down like this
このままではすべての電気が落ちてしまいます
In fact, it is your modification that is hooked up
実際、接続されているのはあなたの変更です
Economic Issues Are Only Identity Issues
経済問題はアイデンティティの問題にすぎない
derivation of issues
問題の導出
It has no way of determining the voting behavior of voters by itself
有権者の投票行動をそれ自体で判断する方法はありません
The main axis of Taiwan's politics is to identify with
台湾政治の主軸は、台湾との共感である。
The main social divide is still material
主要な社会的格差は依然として深刻です
inner identity
内なるアイデンティティ
decide what party it is
どのパーティーかを決める
The economy is used to rationalize the given choices of the electorate
経済は有権者に与えられた選択を正当化するために利用される
This is the Façade
これがファサードです
These three are named Chris Crossley Joe Chan
この3人はクリス・クロスリー・ジョー・チャンという名前です
Could the truth be between the facade
真実はファサードの間にあるのだろうか
It's between Fa Sa's and Replacement
Fa Sa'sとReplacementの間です
Will it be economical and acceptable?
それは経済的で受け入れられるでしょうか？
They are the two axes of competition
これらは競争の 2 つの軸です
And they also cross-penetrate
そして、それらはまた交差浸透します
In terms of identity, let's say we talk about
アイデンティティの観点から、次のことについて話しましょう。
Exclusive Taiwanese
台湾人限定
Exclusively Taiwan's trick
台湾だけのトリック
I am Taiwanese and nothing else
私は台湾人であり、それ以外の何ものでもありません
Taiwanese are also Chinese
台湾人も中国人だよ
Now if we only talk about Chinese
さて、中国語に限って言えば、
already reached the digits
すでにその桁に達しています
Many with Chinese identity are in
中国人のアイデンティティを持つ人がたくさんいる
Taiwanese and Chinese
台湾人と中国人
We call him Tc and the one before that is ET
私たちは彼を Tc と呼びます、その前は ET です
Then what about the economy
そして経済はどうなるのか
Left with redistribution and right with focus field
左が再分配、右がフォーカスフィールド
what am i talking about
私は何を話しているのですか
That is, you can actually have these four combinations.
つまり、実際にはこれら 4 つの組み合わせが可能です。
Then what
じゃあ何
Different regions, groups of people, one field
さまざまな地域、人々のグループ、1 つの分野
The relative salience of identity and economy
アイデンティティと経済の相対的な顕著性
It's Ratacus salient
それはラタカス顕著です
and still different
そしてまだ違う
this may be a comparison
これは比較になるかもしれない
with a detailed view
詳細なビューを使用して
ok let's see now
さて、それでは見てみましょう
Echphal means
エクファルとは
assuming that economics is a more important consideration than identity
経済性がアイデンティティよりも重要な考慮事項であると仮定する
then let's see
それでは見てみましょう
If you identify yourself as Taiwanese
自分を台湾人だと認識している場合
How much intimacy with the other side
相手との親密度はどの程度か
Then your economic attitude is right
それならあなたの経済的態度は正しいです
Do you feel more connected
もっとつながっていると感じますか
a little more contact
もう少し連絡を
A little more is good for the overall economy
もう少し多くても経済全体にとって良いことだ
if you have both
両方持っているなら
You are the pool of congenital
あなたは先天性のプールです
good
良い
That
それか
If we now assume that economic considerations outweigh recognition
ここで、経済的考慮事項が認識を上回ると仮定すると、
So if you are in the lower right corner
右下隅にいる場合
The lower right corner means
右下隅の意味は、
you may or may not be
あなたはいつもこうであるとは限らない
Suppose there is such a person
そういう人がいたとします
For example, he is Japanese
たとえば、彼は日本人です
He opened a factory, or after the cross-strait communication
彼は工場を開設しました。つまり、海峡の両側がつながった後です。
it is beneficial to him
それは彼にとって有益だ
He's in shipping etc.
彼は配送などの仕事をしています。
then he is on the right
それから彼は右側です
But his identification is very strong
しかし彼のアイデンティティは非常に強いです
He is Taiwanese
彼は台湾人です
So the other side has a completely different democracy from mine
つまり、向こう側は私とはまったく異なる民主主義を持っているのです
then you will get an attitude
そうすれば態度がわかるでしょう
If you say that your economy is greater than your recognition
自分の経済が自分の認識よりも大きいと言うなら
these people will barely support
こういう人たちはほとんど支持しないだろう
Why
なぜ
Because the economy is more important
経済の方が大事だから
good
良い
if you are on the left
あなたが左側にいる場合
Let's say you're the husband
あなたが夫だとしましょう
you can't move
あなたは動けない
It's not like money can go to the other side
お金が向こう側に行くわけではない
Then you may be in a traditional industry
そうするとあなたは伝統的な業界にいるかもしれません
You are afraid of competition from the other side
相手との競争が怖い
Then what if your identity is
では、あなたのアイデンティティが次のような場合はどうなるでしょうか。
not Taiwanese
台湾人ではない
I don't accept what you said
私はあなたの言ったことを受け入れません
We are all Chinese
私たちは全員中国人です
what not what to do is chinese
どうしようもないのは中国語だ
Anyway, I heard the word Chinese
とにかく中国語という言葉を聞いた
i can't accept it
受け入れられない
what if that's the case
それが事実ならどうするか
then you just
それならあなたはただ
it's hardcore green
それはハードコアグリーンです
you object
あなたは反対します
Heaven is against this thing
天はこのことに反対している
But we feel more favorable
しかし、私たちはより好意的に感じています
because you are here
あなたがここにいるから
If your golden status is on the left
ゴールデンステータスが左側の場合
But any of you
でも、皆さんの中には誰でも
I feel that the other side is approachable
向こうも近づきやすい気がする
so what attitude do you take
それであなたはどんな態度を取るのですか
If we assume that economic ratios identify
経済比率が特定すると仮定すると、
come more important words
もっと重要な言葉が来ます
then you will hesitate to object
そうすればあなたは反対することを躊躇するでしょう
you still object
あなたはまだ反対しています
Why
なぜ
because you preoccupied the class position
あなたがクラスの地位を占めていたから
but you are hesitant to object
でもあなたは反対することをためらっている
why
なぜ
Because the other side tells you
向こうが言うから
still kind
まだ優しい
So there is such a situation
だからそういう状況があるんだよ
ok let's go down
よし、降りよう
will make it clearer
より明確になります
Well now it's time for the whole
さて、いよいよ全体の時間です
This is the last paragraph
これが最後の段落です
as if we were to see
もし私たちが見たら
There may be an axis
軸はあるかもしれない
If this turns
これが変わったら
how do we do this research
この研究はどうやって行うのですか
First
初め
we should know
私たちは知っておくべきです
political party
政治団体
What is perception and countermeasures
認識と対策とは
picture
像
we just made this
私たちはこれを作ったばかりです
The other is to look at voters
もう一つは有権者に注目することです
as far as voters are concerned
有権者に関する限り
identity and economy
アイデンティティと経済
relative salience is what
相対的な顕著性とは何か
Is it a replacement, a performance, or a crossover?
それは代替品でしょうか、パフォーマンスでしょうか、それともクロスオーバーでしょうか?
if it is replaced
交換された場合
That is, if everyone thinks
つまり、みんながそう思ったら
economics is more important
経済のほうが大事だよ
Approval is not that important
承認はそれほど重要ではありません
Then I voted for this line
それから私はこの行に投票しました
will emerge along this axis of the economy
この経済軸に沿って出現するだろう
beyond identity
アイデンティティを超えて
That is to say, if I am left
つまり、もし私が残されたら
i will vote
私は投票します
Let us suppose
仮定してみましょう
That is to say, if the DPP moves to the left
つまり、民進党が左傾化すると、
to develop words
言葉を発展させる
I'll vote to the left
私は左に投票します
If I am right
私が正しければ
I vote on the right side
私は右側に投票します
what is my own identity
自分のアイデンティティとは何ですか
this is not important
これは重要ではありません
If it is appearance
見た目なら
that is to say it is fake
つまり偽物です
everyone basically knows
基本的には誰もが知っています
Vote with your own approval
ご自身の承認を得て投票してください
Then I voted this way
それから私はこうして投票しました
will emerge along the axis of that identity
そのアイデンティティの軸に沿って現れます
which length makes me feel
どの長さが私を感じさせますか
His identity is the same as mine
彼のアイデンティティは私と同じです
I will vote for him
私は彼に投票します
Whether the party is left or right
政党が左派か右派か
what if it's a cross
それが十字架だったらどうなるか
My voting line would be somewhere in between
私の投票ラインはその中間になるでしょう
i will become a slash
私はスラッシュになります
well what exactly
さて、正確には何ですか
if we make it
それができたら
as long as we vote all
私たちが全員に投票する限り
The vote of the Kuomintang
国民党の投票
put it in
中に入れて
In this diagram of identity and economy
このアイデンティティと経済の図では
mark it up
マークアップする
Then if we see the situation
それで状況を見てみると
Those who voted for the Kuomintang and the blue
国民党と青に投票した人たち
it's on the top piece
それは上の部分にあります
who voted for the Democratic Progressive Party
民進党に投票した人は
it's in the block below
下のブロックにあります
we can find out
私たちは知ることができます
In fact voters
実際、有権者は
The emphasis is on recognition
認識を重視する
Why
なぜ
because it doesn't matter if you're left or right
右か左かは関係ないから
How do I know if you are left or right?
あなたが左か右かをどうやって知ることができますか?
May ask by survey
アンケートで質問する場合があります
Then wait and see how your left attitude is
それから待って、あなたの左の態度がどうなるかを見てください
so i know if you're left or right
だから私はあなたが左か右か知っています
whether you are left or right
あなたが左であろうと右であろうと
As long as I consider myself Taiwanese
私が自分を台湾人だと思っている限り、
I will vote green
私は緑に投票します
As long as I feel that I am identifying with Taiwanese
自分が台湾人であると感じている限り
Chinese again
また中国語
i will vote blue
私は青に投票します
Regardless of my own preference of being left versus right
左か右かという私自身の好みとは関係なく
that's my vote
それが私の投票です
But I mean another word
しかし、私が言いたいのは別の言葉です
like this key
この鍵のように
Still agree with this axis
今でもこの軸に同意
This axis divides the two kinds of people
この軸が二種類の人間を分ける
This axis also splits two kinds of votes
この軸も 2 種類の票を分割します
You vote with your approval
あなたの承認を得て投票します
So something like this
それで、このようなもの
we're talking a lot of stuff now
私たちは今たくさんのことを話しています
In fact, Ai is all fake
実はアイちゃんは全部偽物なんです
when i voted down
私が反対票を投じたとき
I am voting according to my sensibility
自分の感性に従って投票してます
But if we make this picture and change it like this
でももし私たちの写真がこのように作られたら
how is that
それはどうですか
That means I agree with people on the right
つまり、私は右の人たちに同意するということです
Whether it's my golden status
それが私の黄金のステータスかどうか
Or my opinion of where the country is in this economy
あるいは、この国がこの経済の中でどのような位置にあるのかについての私の意見
Policies, etc.
政策等
I am on the right
私は右側です
I am right
私は正しいですよ
then no matter
それなら構わない
I said I am Taiwanese
台湾人だと言いました
Or I am both Taiwanese and Chinese
あるいは、私は台湾人と中国人の両方です
no matter what my identity is
私のアイデンティティが何であっても
i vote like this
私はこのように投票します
then if i was left
それで私が残っていたら
Just my golden one
ちょうど私の黄金のもの
Or I think the government should reduce the gap between rich and poor
あるいは政府は貧富の差を縮めるべきだと思う
The government should increase welfare spending
政府は福祉支出を増額すべきである
The government should tax some people more
政府は一部の人々にもっと税金を課すべきだ
It's like I'm the one who thinks so
そう思っているのは私だけのようです
my kind of person
私のような人
It doesn't matter if I say I'm Taiwanese
台湾人だと言っても関係ない
Taiwanese or Chinese
台湾人とか中国人とか
No matter what my identity is
私のアイデンティティが何であれ
I always vote green and vote for the Democratic Progressive Party.
私はいつも緑に投票し、民進党に投票します。
Then I found out the results of the poll
その後、投票結果を知りました
This line is like this
この行はこんな感じです
This line just cuts between the left and right
この線はちょうど左右の間を切っています
Same as left and right cut
左右カット同様
So when I voted
それで私が投票したとき
regardless of my approval
私の承認に関係なく
I vote based on my financial interests
私は自分の経済的利益に基づいて投票します
This word is to replace
この言葉に代わるのは
But if what we get is this
でも、もし私たちが得たものがこれだったとしたら
i'm not messing with amoebas
私はアメーバをいじっているわけではありません
Although they look a bit like
少し似ていますが、
If we look at something like this
このようなものを見ると
that's a cross
それは十字架です
what happens when you cross
交差すると何が起こるか
let's watch this
これを見ましょう
who is this
これは誰ですか
it's economic you're on the right
あなたは右側にいるのが経済的です
ok
Ok
Then you should vote blue
それなら青に投票すべきだ
But what about agreeing?
しかし、同意する場合はどうでしょうか？
you are guard taiwanese
あなたは警備員の台湾人です
But you still voted blue
でもあなたはまだ青に投票した
said for them
彼らのために言った
economy over identity
アイデンティティよりも経済
so there will be
だからあるでしょう
Such a piece of blue voter
あんな青い投票者
that's also in the lower right corner
それも右下隅にあります
also the same
また同じです
These people should be economically right-wingers
こういう人たちは経済右翼であるべきだ
But in terms of identity, he is Taiwanese.
しかし、アイデンティティという点では、彼は台湾人です。
He voted green
彼は緑に投票した
What about these people?
この人たちについてはどうですか？
His reason is more important than
彼の理由はそれよりも重要です
He is more emotional than rational
彼は理性的というより感情的だ
He is voting with approval
彼は承認を得て投票している
if we appear
私たちが現れたら
Then these two pieces are explained like this
そして、この2つの作品は次のように説明されます
What about this piece?
この作品はどうでしょうか？
it's just the opposite
それはちょうど反対です
he's in the upper left corner
彼は左上隅にいます
how do you say this
どのようにこれを言うのですか
That is to say, economically, he is on the left
つまり経済的には左派だ
he should throw left
彼は左に投げるべきだ
So he should vote green
だから彼は緑に投票すべきだ
but
しかし
His identity is Chinese
彼のアイデンティティは中国人です
Also Taiwanese, he should have voted blue
同じ台湾人なら青に投票すべきだった
He should vote blue emotionally
彼は感情的に青に投票すべきだ
His economy should be voted green
彼の経済は賛成票を投じられるべきだ
if he casts blue
彼が青をキャストした場合
mean what
どういういみ
It means he is more emotional than you
それは彼があなたよりも感情的であることを意味します
If this piece appears
この作品が出たら
what is this piece
この作品は何ですか
also the same
また同じです
what is it
それは何ですか
It is left on the golden position
ゴールデンポジションに残っています
OK
OK
but
しかし
His identity above
上記の彼のアイデンティティ
Is the Chinese also this Taiwanese?
この中国人も台湾人なのでしょうか？
He voted green
彼は緑に投票した
what does that mean
どういう意味ですか
express his economic considerations
彼の経済的考慮を表明する
beyond his approval of the above considerations
上記の考慮事項に対する彼の承認を超えて
Just if the two things are interpenetrating
二つのものが相互浸透しているとしたら
Then the axis we see is not like this
そうすると私たちが見ている軸はこんなものではない
if that is recognition
それが認識だとしたら
not so
そうではありません
If so, it is economical but
そうすれば経済的ですが、
so
それで
Such words mean
そのような言葉の意味は、
What about my lower right corner and upper left corner?
右下隅と左上隅はどうでしょうか?
How was it graded
どのように採点されましたか
This means that identity and economy interpenetrate
これは、アイデンティティと経済が相互浸透することを意味します
For some people, two identifications are more important
一部の人にとっては、2 つの身分証明書の方が重要です
For some people the economy is more important
一部の人にとっては経済の方が重要です
bottom right and bottom left
右下と左下
I can't look at the upper right corner and the lower left corner
右上も左下も見ない
Because it's perfect blue and green
完璧な青と緑だから
I'll look at the bottom right and top left
右下と左上を見てみます
They have interaction conflicts
彼らは互いに衝突します
very anxious
とても不安です
my finances push me aside
私の財政が私を脇に押しのける
My finances push me the other way
私の財政は私を別の方向へ押し進めます
The result is split
結果は分かれる
some people voted blue
何人かは青に投票した
some people voted green
何人かは緑に投票した
This is to represent its two crosses
これは2つの十字架を表すためです
interact with
との相互作用
We can dampen the shock with something like this
このようなもので衝撃を和らげることができます
Of course now
もちろん今も
For example, the one from TDS
たとえば、TDSのもの
I have read their latest survey
最新の調査を読みました
There is a question about left and right
左右について質問です
still bad question
まだ悪い質問
so there is no way to catch it clearly
だからそれをはっきりと捉える方法はない
But this piece of recognition
しかし、この認識は
has developed a lot
たくさん発展しました
good
良い
So for the main axis of political competition in Taiwan
台湾における政治的競争の主軸について
research on whether to transform
変身するかどうかの研究
I think it has great theoretical
素晴らしい理論を持っていると思います
For Taiwan's political and
台湾の政治と
realistic
現実的な
closely related to our actual politics
私たちの現実の政治と密接に関係している
Taiwan's foreign relations
台湾の対外関係
Regardless of cross-strait relations
海峡を越えた関係に関係なく
Or Taiwan-US relations have a major impact
あるいは台湾と米国の関係が大きな影響を与える
Therefore, it is a research worthy of high attention
したがって、非常に注目に値する研究である
Dense
密集
Thanks
ありがとう
Welcome to ask questions
ご質問を歓迎します
come please come
来てください来てください
before asking the question
質問する前に
I just listened to director Wu's speech, I believe
呉監督のスピーチを聞いたところだと思います
There is a passage inside Hamrabi's flower
ハムラビの花の中に通路がある
Don't fight too long with female enemies
女性の敵とあまり長く戦わないでください
become like him
彼のようになる
Especially when you mentioned Ma Yingjun's Tsai Ing-wen
特に馬英軍の蔡英文さんについて言及したときは。
more and more like
ますます好きになる
do you believe this
あなたはこれを信じますか
Don't fight your enemies for too long
敵とあまり長く戦わないでください
so as not to become more and more like him
ますます彼に似てしまわないように
come i want to ask
来て聞きたいです
Thanks
ありがとう
so to sum up
要約すると
then i want to say many times
それから何度も言いたいです
You will also be normal to come to which one do you think
あなたも普通に来るでしょう、どっちだと思いますか？
will be guided very closely
非常に丁寧に指導されます
achievable
達成可能
So take care of what you need
だから必要なものは大事にしてね
make the problem come back
問題を元に戻す
under normal circumstances
通常の状況下で
or Taiwanese society
あるいは台湾社会
I think this seems to be more
こちらの方が多いような気がします
is normal from to
からは正常です
The player's problem
選手の問題
So imagine in this direction
この方向を想像してください
is it to be cared about
気にすることですか？
they'll pose like this
彼らはこんなポーズをとるだろう
this question is very good
この質問はとても良いです
I agree with what you said
私はあなたの言うことに同意します
That is to say, not everything can be seen as
つまり、すべてが次のように見えるわけではありません
society decides
社会が決める
social determinism
社会的決定論
I think there are two things to look at
見るべき点は2つあると思います
the first is
一つ目は
Of course, we can't see it as top-down
もちろんトップダウンで見ることはできません
In fact, every political party must
実際、どの政党もそうしなければなりません。
Want to maintain the battlefield in your favor
戦場を有利に保ちたい
So if I'm in a battlefield I can beat you up
だからもし戦闘になったら君を倒すことができるよ
You said you don't want to play with me in this battlefield
この戦場では私と遊びたくないって言ったよね
you're going to open another game
別のゲームを開こうとしています
Then of course I don't want to go there
それならもちろん行きたくない
but the problem is
しかし問題は
Recently my battlefield is real or your battlefield is real
最近、私の戦場が現実になった、あるいはあなたの戦場が現実になった
we have to appeal to the voters
私たちは有権者に訴えなければなりません
right
右
Because I'm big on my field
私は自分の分野では偉いから
Then I said I've been reading show
それから私は番組を読んでいると言いました
Then I realized that no one came to see my ring
それから私は誰も私の指輪を見に来ないことに気づきました
He just went to see him so long
彼はただ長い間会いに行っただけだ
In the end, I just passed
結局、そのまま通過してしまいました
So I think the manipulation from top to bottom
だから私は上から下への操作だと思います
has an inherent limitation
本質的に制限がある
This limitation is an effect on a larger environment
この制限はより大規模な環境に影響を与えます
what is the big environment
大きな環境とは何ですか
In my whole analysis framework
私の分析フレームワーク全体では
I think
私が思うに
Taiwan's economic development
台湾の経済発展
is a very important factor
非常に重要な要素です
And this factor makes voters think more and more about the economy
この要因により、有権者は経済についてますます考えるようになります
But the Democratic Party does not mean
しかし、民主党はそういうつもりはありません
Europe and the United States advocate the economy
欧米は経済を擁護する
So the DPP is attracted to this venue by me
だから民進党は私にこの会場に惹かれたのです
I went to the KMT basically to identify with that venue
私は基本的にその会場に共感するために国民党に行きました
was beaten worse than Qing
清よりもひどい仕打ちを受けた
Then the proportion said
すると割合はこう言った
Okay, I won't come with you
わかった、一緒には行かないよ
I'm half throwing in the towel here
ここで半分タオルを投げます
Then let's play this now
それでは、今すぐこれをプレイしましょう
it's not actually the action
それは実際の行動ではありません
if it doesn't do the first action
最初のアクションを実行しない場合
The DPP can still pull it back
民進党はまだ撤回できる
So I think
それで私は思います
The general environment prompts this axis to change
一般的な環境はこの軸の変化を促します
Of course the Kuomintang has some of its strategies
もちろん国民党にはいくつかの戦略がある
There is more to this shift
この変化には続きがあります
but you may ask a question
でも質問してもいいですよ
You said, let's look at Lebanon
あなたは言った、レバノンを見てみましょう
Let's see Iraq
イラクを見てみよう
We are optimistic about those Kuomintang
私たちは国民党について楽観的です
Relatives are finished
親戚は終わった
These guys are still fighting, right?
こいつらはまだ戦ってるんだよね？
The rift where they fought each other
彼らが争った亀裂
either else only read
それ以外の場合は読み取りのみ
otherwise only hit
それ以外の場合はヒットのみ
The professional school hates the virtual school
専門学校はバーチャルスクールを嫌う
Virtual faction hates that Kurd
仮想派はクルド人を嫌っている
and then make it like this
そしてそれをこのようにします
So I think another factor is
ですから、別の要因があると思います
Identity Differences in Taiwan
台湾におけるアイデンティティの違い
It's not that deep
そんなに深くないよ
it can be shifted to this side of the economy
経済のこちら側にシフトできる
When the environment will favor its transfer
環境がその転送に有利になる時期
If its cut is very
カットが非常に大きい場合
I'm afraid there is no way
残念ながら仕方がありません
let me give you an example
例をあげましょう
We have good show scholars coming to Taiwan for a meeting
優秀なショー学者が会議のために台湾に来ています
then we talk to him
それから私たちは彼に話します
wow we're a blue and green opposite
わあ、私たちは青と緑の反対側です
Ours is badly weathered
うちは風化が悪い
us people hate people
私たち人間は人を憎む
then they told me
それから彼らは私に言いました
Really
本当
He and I go outside to see if you are different
彼と私はあなたが違うかどうかを確認するために外に出ます
What am I talking about?
私は何を話しているのでしょうか？
we are just different
私たちはただ違うだけです
I tell you
私はあなたに言います
if you go to israel
イスラエルに行くなら
what is an israeli
イスラエル人とは何ですか
what is an arab
アラブとは何ですか
I can see clearly
はっきり見えます
they look different
彼らは違って見える
speak differently
違う言い方をする
Doing different is living in a different place
違うことをするということは、違う場所に住むということだ
what about you
あなたはどうですか
so just
これだけ
we feel
私達は感じる
The conflict is that Skeleton is here
矛盾はスケルトンがここにいることだ
In fact, relatively speaking, it is relatively mild
実際、比較的穏やかに言えます
because I feel
感じているから
On the one hand there is this
一方ではこれがあります
On the other hand there is a big shock
一方で大きなショックもある
causing Taiwan to swing between these two principal axes
台湾がこれら 2 つの主軸の間で揺れ動く原因となっている
is easier
より簡単です
At least that's what I've seen so far
少なくとも私がこれまで見てきたのはそうでした
so
それで
But because of this time becomes
でもこの時期だからこそ、
So it is a process of National Arts University
国立芸術大学のプロセスです
But the Democratic Party
しかし民主党は
The KMT will not take gold for this
国民党はこれには金を受け取らないだろう
Transfiguration University is because of the six
変容大学があるのは6人だから
But the KMT thing is a kind of
しかし国民党というのは一種の
won't become the whole combination
すべての組み合わせにはなりません
The Democratic Party can't think so far
民主党はそこまで考えられない
Because when the DPP has reached the economic
なぜなら、民進党が経済的安定に達したとき、
when this game comes
このゲームが来たら
And when the KMT is the government
そして国民党が政府になると
It's just desperate to improve the economy
経済を良くするのに必死だ
It must first maintain the situation
まずは現状を維持しなければならない
As for what you said, maybe in the long run
あなたが言ったことについては、おそらく長期的には
really become like that
本当にそうなる
it can't handle it
それは耐えられない
it's all about the next presidential election
すべては次の大統領選挙に関することだ
who else
他に誰
this one
これです
i'm curious that is to say
つまり気になる
Before we discuss these political rivalries in Taiwan
台湾における政治的対立について議論する前に
compete with the economy
経済と競争する
When these active conversions
これらのアクティブなコンバージョンが発生したとき
External influence on Taiwan
台湾に対する外部の影響
Is it getting smaller
小さくなってるのかな
That is to say, Taiwan talks about many things behind closed doors.
つまり、台湾は密室でいろいろなことを話しているのです。
Changes to the future under such development
そうした発展の中で起こる未来の変化
Are we actually
私たちは本当にいますか
The more lack of a comparative force from the outside
外部からの力が相対的に不足すればするほど、
Because your two pancakes are so much better
あなたの2つのビスケットはとても美味しいから
Then you lack a possibility to look outside
そうなると外を見る機会がなくなる
Just compare the direction of our media
私たちのメディアの方向性を比較してください
Some effects of receding in the middle
途中で後退することによるいくつかの影響
Because I often feel like you turn off the TV
あなたがテレビを消しているように感じることがよくあるから
You think the world isn't so bad
あなたは世界はそれほど悪くないと思っています
But when you turn on the TV
でもテレビをつけると
In fact, many topics are not worth listening to.
実際、多くのトピックは聞く価値がありません。
because there is little room for rational discourse
合理的な議論の余地がほとんどないからです
that negative impact
その悪影響
Is it what you think it will be
それはあなたが思っているとおりですか
drive change in our entire society
社会全体に変化をもたらす
I think there are two parts to the story
この話には2つの部分があると思います
The first people in Taiwan are relatively lacking
台湾の最初の人々は比較的不足しています
habit of looking outside
外を見る習慣
Following the environment of the media has a lot to do with it
メディア環境に従うことが大きく関係している
this is a serious problem
これは深刻な問題です
For example, we don't really understand
たとえば、よくわかりませんが、
Is our government doing well?
私たちの政府はうまくやっているでしょうか？
What does that mean
どういう意味ですか
Because I don't know what's going on in other countries
他国がどうなっているのか分からないので
then let me give you an example
それなら例をあげましょう
Like Merkel, he is a big camp
メルケル首相と同様、彼は大きな陣営だ
recently in germany
最近ドイツで
The most important reason is that
最も重要な理由は、
Because Germans still look around
ドイツ人はまだ周りを見回しているから
It's even worse for France to step on Greece like this
フランスがこのようにギリシャを踏みにじるのはさらに悪いことだ
Italy is outrageous
イタリアはとんでもない
Spain is doomed
スペインは破滅する運命にある
All Europe is Germany
ヨーロッパはすべてドイツだ
very good
とても良い
So they think Merkel is amazing
だから彼らはメルケル首相が素晴らしいと思っている
this is a comparison
これは比較です
Because Europeans are so close to each other
ヨーロッパ人はお互いにとても近いので
Do people in Taiwan have an overall international outlook?
台湾の人々は全体的な国際的な視野を持っていますか?
Then understand the environment we are in now
そして今私たちが置かれている環境を理解する
and then judge our government by that
そしてそれによって私たちの政府を判断します
I think we lack the ability to look outside
私たちには外を見る能力が欠けていると思う
for better or worse
良くも悪くも
Let's talk about this
これについて話しましょう
This is a
これは
Recently, a certain station is trying to pull our field of vision out
最近、とある局が僕らの視界を引き出そうとしている
I wish him luck, but I really don't know how it will end up.
彼の幸運を祈りますが、最終的にはどうなるかわかりません
In the past, there were quite a few programs that focused on international
かつては、国際的な内容に焦点を当てた番組が数多くありました。
It didn't seem to go so well afterward.
その後はあまりうまくいかなかったようです。
OK but the other way around
OK、でもその逆
On the other hand, is there any influence from outside?
一方で、外部からの影響はありますか？
that's the worst
それは最悪です
The outside world greatly affects us
外の世界は私たちに大きな影響を与えます
But we don't know or we don't feel much
でも私たちは知らない、あるいはあまり感じていない
External economic forces have trouble with Taiwan
外部経済勢力が台湾と問題を抱えている
We are so spiritually dependent on an outward looking economy
私たちは精神的に外向きの経済に依存している
too much influence
影響力が大きすぎる
There is a financial tsunami outside
外では金融津波が起きている
Isn't Taiwan the same as being blown up?
台湾も爆破されたのと同じではないか？
Outside the economy, even the above things
経済の外では、上記のことさえも
The situation on the other side
向こう側の状況
The influence of the mainland on Taiwan is growing
台湾に対する大陸の影響力が強まる
This itself is an objective fact
それ自体は客観的事実です
But his rulers are in no rush
しかし彼の統治者たちは急いでいない
fuck this thing
クソこんなこと
so that its influence suffers
その影響力が弱まるように
I think it's smart to understand that
それを理解するのが賢明だと思う
But its influence is growing
しかしその影響力は増大している
So let alone the United States
だからアメリカどころか
and then a bunch of stuff
それからたくさんのもの
Okay, so the outside world has a lot of influence on us.
そうですね、外の世界は私たちに大きな影響を与えます。
But our understanding of the outside world is very small
しかし、外の世界に対する私たちの理解は非常に狭いです
I think it's the worst combination
最悪の組み合わせだと思う
A better combination should be
より良い組み合わせはこうあるべきです
The influence of the outside world on us is limited
外界が私たちに与える影響は限られています
But I understand the outside world very well
でも私は外の世界をよく理解しています
Look how good it is, don't you?
見てください、とても良いですよね？
Even I affect the outside
私でもまだ外側に影響を与えています
Then there is one more thing to say
それからもう一つあります
The field because we have a great influence
影響力が大きいですからこの分野は
But we also know the outside world well
しかし、私たちは外の世界のこともよく知っています
that's good too
それもいいですね
If it weren't for the outside world's little influence on us
外の世界が私たちに与える影響が少なかったら
we don't know the outside world
私たちは外の世界を知りません
Ah, you're old, at least count
ああ、あなたは年をとった、少なくとも数えてください
We're messed up by outside influences, right?
私たちは外部の影響によってめちゃくちゃになってしまいますよね？
how could we not
どうしてできなかったのか
But what we know about the outside world
しかし、私たちが外の世界について知っていること
Actually less
実際にはもっと少ない
Ah I
ああ、私
There must be many of you
皆さんの中にもたくさんいるはずです
this is
これは
on our computer
私たちのコンピュータ上で
Spend a lot of time blah blah blah blah blah
たくさんの時間を過ごしてください
i have a worry
心配がある
as soon as i found out our tv
私たちのテレビを知ってすぐに
What is the news on the broadcast?
放送ではどんなニュースが流れますか？
let it truncate from internet speed
インターネット速度から切り捨ててみましょう
Then you see this is exaggerated
そうすれば、これは誇張されていることがわかります
it turns here
ここで曲がる
also met someone
誰かにも会った
You see, this knight just bounced off
ほら、この騎士は跳ね返されたばかりだ
Woooooo, auntie, play it ten times
うわー、おばちゃん、10回遊んで
And here's one of his most important news
そしてこれが彼の大きなニュースの一つです
something like this
このようなもの
then what what
じゃあ何だ
Then take a picture of that computer
次に、そのコンピューターの写真を撮ります
What do netizens say
ネチズンは何と言いますか
then what is the comment
じゃあコメントは何ですか
And he's not the only one
そして彼だけではありません
This station does this
この局はこれをやります
That station thinks that if I don't do this
私がこうしないとあの局はこう思う
I seem to be behind
遅れているようです
he did the same
彼も同じことをした
I watch different channels
いろいろなチャンネルを見ています
He is still the same
彼は今も同じです
the screen on the computer
コンピューターの画面
This, this, if the medium of the Internet
これが、これが、インターネットという媒体なら
with traditional media
従来のメディアを使った
are highly concentrated in
に高度に集中している
to us
私たちに
Everything related to daily life
日常生活に関わるあらゆること
But it's all together
でもそれは全部一緒だよ
this little piece
この小さな部分
but didn't care
でも気にしなかった
the big world outside
外の大きな世界
Words that have had a huge impact on us
私たちに大きな影響を与えた言葉
then we are dangerous
それなら私たちは危険です
Because we are not very strong
私たちはそれほど強くないので、
so i'm worried
だから心配です
so i ask again
それでもう一度尋ねます
So if it goes like this
それでこうなったら
Look at our media and the Internet
私たちのメディアやインターネットを見てください
Let's say they want to bomb an event
彼らがイベントを爆撃したいとしよう
or an issue
または問題
Like the one a while ago
少し前のやつのように
soldier that red
赤い兵士
red mid autumn
真っ赤な中秋
To Hong Zhongqiu's agenda
ホン・ジョンチウの議題へ
that is
あれは
many people would think that
多くの人はそう思うだろう
he is a civic movement
彼は市民運動の一員です
is a movement of civil disobedience
それは市民的不服従の運動です
then on top of the blue and green parties
それから青と緑のパーティーの上に
spontaneous
自発
Spontaneous demands of the common people
庶民の自然な要求
government reform
政府改革
But from a certain point of view
しかし、ある視点から見ると
because every day the media
なぜなら毎日メディアが
play like this
こうやって遊ぶ
That's how much of it is the spontaneous thinking of real citizens
それくらい本物の国民の自発的な考えだ
That, or how do we break through this situation?
それ、あるいはこの状況をどう打開するか？
Such a dangerous situation in Taiwan
台湾はとても危険な状況です
That is to say, we are actually a very fragile economy
つまり、私たちは実際には非常に脆弱な経済なのです
But we don't care about the changes we find around us
でも私たちは周囲の変化を気にしません
I think it's like Hong Zhongqiu.
ホン・ジョンチウに似ていると思います。
Did you say there was manipulation?
操作があったと言いましたか？
Did you say there is media amplification?
メディアの増幅があると言いましたか？
But you said he has touched a lot of people?
でも、彼は多くの人に影響を与えたと言いましたね？
It will come out automatically, too.
これも自動で出てきます。
I know there are a lot of them, it's just like the civil world
そういう人がたくさんいるのはわかってる、それはまさに市民世界と同じだ
What faces too much correlation
相関関係が強すぎるもの
Which means he wasn't very involved at all.
つまり、彼はあまり関与していなかったということです。
For example, Mommy is at home
たとえば、ママは家にいます
After he saw this, he hated the sky
これを見て彼は空が嫌いになった
Because why does he think he is a child
何故なら彼は自分を子供だと思うから
Looks like his kid is hurting too
お子さんも痛がっているようです
So you said that the speculation on the Internet is so fierce
インターネット上の憶測がとても激しいとあなたは言いましたね
And it seems like there's nothing fair about it
そして、それについては何も公平ではないようです
not bad at all
悪くない、全く
I think we lack a common ideal
私たちには共通の理想が欠けていると思う
room for debate
議論の余地
we lack such a thing
私たちにはそのようなものが欠けています
one that lets in different voices
さまざまな声を入れられるもの
And as long as you come in
そして、あなたが入ってくる限り、
let's just say you're in the middle of this
あなたはこの真っ只中にいるとしましょう
no passion
情熱がない
but speak well
でもよく話す
Then many people would like to see
そうすれば多くの人が見たいでしょう
such a thing
そんなこと
We lack that public forum
私たちにはそのような公開の場が欠けています
we all have a stand
私たち全員が立場を持っています
If you say to watch this station
この局を見ると言ったら
then his talk show
それから彼のトークショー
He will also find a partner
彼もパートナーを見つけるでしょう
The people who are in the camp are coming
キャンプにいる人たちが来ています
but then attack him
しかしその後彼を攻撃する
beat him up
彼を殴る
Then see him speechless
それから彼が言葉を失っているのを見てください
Right
右
there too
そこにもある
but this is not
しかし、これはそうではありません
Then the whole discourse
それから、談話全体が
have that one-sided nature
そんな一方的な性質を持っている
but there is no place
でも場所がない
be able to say no matter what you look like
見た目に関係なく言えること
emotionally not
感情的にはそうではない
how unacceptable
なんとも受け入れがたい
But you let him finish talking properly
でもあなたは彼にきちんと話し終えてもらいました
then listen to
それから聞いてください
I have my own reasons
私には私なりの理由があります
this public domain
このパブリックドメイン
I think in this field
この分野ではそう思います
if bigger
もっと大きかったら
our whole society will be different
私たちの社会全体が変わるでしょう
But we are relatively lacking in this area now
しかし、今ではこの分野が比較的不足しています
We've done a great job of pasting tickets.
チケットの貼り付けも上手にできました。
So you're saying we don't have a free press?
つまり、我が国には報道の自由がないということですか？
Oh, why not?
ああ、どうしてでしょうか？
but we
しかし、我々
In a few examples
いくつかの例で
If we talk about politics, this goes to one side
政治の話をすると、それは一方に偏ってしまいます
Because your press is actually a
なぜなら、あなたの報道機関は実際には
to fight for the market, right?
市場のために戦うためですよね？
So can you do politically incorrect reporting?
では、政治的に間違った報道ができるだろうか？
It's actually stressful
実はストレスなんです
So I think there's a civic culture
だから市民文化があると思う
A culture that allows us to address these issues
これらの問題に対処できる文化
able to make a rational argument
合理的な議論ができる
we have seen this kind of thing
私たちはこのようなものを見てきました
it's a pity
それは残念だ
I think we should find a way to make something like this come out
このようなものを世に出す方法を見つけるべきだと思います
I don't care about individual issues now
今は個別の問題には興味がない
I mean anything on this topic
このトピックについては何でも言いたい
There should be something like this
このようなものがあるはずです
Teacher, I want to go back to some of the arguments mentioned in your speech just now
先生、今のスピーチで言及された議論のいくつかに戻りたいのですが
and then do some clarification
それからいくつかの説明をします
That’s what the teacher just mentioned about identity and economics.
それが先ほど先生がアイデンティティと経済についておっしゃったことです。
At a time of shift as the axis of political competition could be his electoral defeat
政治的競争の軸が転換する時期に、選挙での敗北はあり得る
So his party started to have some shifts
それで彼のパーティーはいくつかのシフトを開始しました
Then I remember when Chen Shui-bian came to power in 2000
そして、2000年に陳水扁が政権を握ったときのことを思い出します。
He mentions four emails
彼は4通のメールについて言及した
Then
それから
Shouting slogans to fight the economy
経済と戦うためにスローガンを叫ぶ
Then have a development meeting
その後開発会議を開きます
At that time, it felt like he was freezing his identity too.
その時、彼も自分のアイデンティティを凍り付けているように感じました。
Instead, the axis of competition should be developed towards the economic aspect.
むしろ、競争軸は経済面に向けて発展させるべきである。
until that said
そう言われるまでは
When Dianjia was avoiding the dark, he began to go to extremes
ディアンジアが暗闇を避けていたとき、彼は極端な行為をし始めました
So I started to bring up the issue of recognition again.
そこで私は再び認識の問題を取り上げ始めました。
That
それか
My first question is whether there is any way to answer the teacher's speech today
私の最初の質問は、今日の先生のスピーチに答える方法はあるかどうかです。
For example, in political operations like this, they are
たとえば、このような政治活動では、
When the axis of my political competition shifts
自分の政治的競争の軸が変わるとき
like Chen Shuibian
陳水扁みたいに
His selection strategy at that time
当時の彼の選考戦略
Why didn't I continue to expand the development of the economic axis
なぜ経済軸の発展を拡大し続けなかったのか
Instead I turned to the competition to identify with this
代わりに、私はこれを認識するために競争に目を向けました
The second question is
2番目の質問は、
The teacher is in the conclusion part
先生は結論部分にいます
Just mentioned three possibilities
先ほど 3 つの可能性について述べました
what i want to know is
私が知りたいのは
It's the teacher, if you yourself
あなた自身なら、それは先生です
You must now represent Taiwan's future politics
あなたはこれから台湾の将来の政治を代表しなければなりません
development or society as a whole
開発や社会全体
Whole development of images to make a whole paragraph or assertion of words
段落全体または言葉の主張を作成するための画像全体の展開
Do you think Taiwan is moving towards this replacement performance or crossover
台湾はこの代替パフォーマンスまたはクロスオーバーに向かって進んでいると思いますか
It’s the teacher, which direction do you think it is more?
先生です、どちらの方向だと思いますか？
Thank you for these two questions
この 2 つの質問に感謝します
about the first question
最初の質問について
In fact, this is a big framework
実はこれが大きな枠組みなんです
It is unlikely that it can account for every individual
すべての個人を説明できる可能性は低い
How about you Bian
ビアンさんはどうですか
I think it's Taiwan's identity energy
それは台湾のアイデンティティのエネルギーだと思います
not fully mobilized
完全に動員されていない
so when he tapped him again
それで彼がもう一度彼をたたいたとき
he actually got a nice reaction
実際彼はいい反応をしてくれました
only if he keeps going
彼が進み続けた場合にのみ
to practice this energy
このエネルギーを実践するために
At last he found that he had
ついに彼は自分が持っていることに気づきました
when approaching the gas mother
ガスマザーに近づくと
at this time will be forced to transfer
この時点で強制的に転送されます
so everyone is trial and error
だからみんな試行錯誤してる
when the leaders of these parties
これらの政党の指導者が
When deciding which strategy to adopt
どの戦略を採用するかを決めるとき
He can't do that
彼にはそんなことはできない
true to his best
最善を尽くして誠実に
he's trying to do it
彼はそれをしようとしている
Ah Bian's strategy at that time
当時のアビアンの戦略
In fact, it's not just about staying out of the dark.
実際、それは単に暗闇から遠ざかることだけではありません。
It should be said that in 2003
2003年にそう言うべきです
even earlier
もっと早くに
2001 2002
2001年2002年
One country actually came out when Nauru established diplomatic relations
ナウルが国交を樹立したとき、実際に1つの国が出てきました。
Then in 2003
そして2003年に
There is a SARS on it
そこにはSARSがあります
then next
それから次へ
connected to
に接続されています
Because Sha Zukang from the mainland is not there
大陸の沙祖康がいないから
Tell me who cares about you or what
誰があなたのことを気にかけているのか教えてください
At that time, Taiwan felt
その時、台湾はこう感じた
wow we look like this
わあ、私たちはこう見えます
We have no way to be received in the world
私たちは世界に受け入れられる方法がない
You still feel sorry for us
あなたはまだ私たちを気の毒に思っています
He also said that if you want to talk to the World Health Organization
彼はまた、もし世界保健機関と話したいなら、とも言いました。
as if there is any connection through it
あたかもそれを通して何かつながりがあるかのように
This thing suddenly becomes a
このことは突然、
Strong, intensified, this thing
強くて強くなって、これ
Then in 2003
そして2003年に
When the Democratic Progressive Party celebrates
民進党が祝うとき
Did he mention three tasks?
彼は 3 つのタスクについて言及しましたか?
At this time, it has already been highly tuned out.
現時点では、すでに高度に調整されています。
Then there was the matter of the referendum
それから住民投票の問題もあった
So I think the operation of its election issue is
したがって、選挙問題の運用は次のようになると思います。
You said there was nothing wrong with the economy in the beginning
最初は経済には何の問題もなかったって言ってたよね
But the economy at that time
でも当時の経済は
just a very unfavorable situation
ただ非常に不利な状況です
Since 2000 began to decline
2000年以降は減少し始めた
2001 Didn't you say rich
2001年 金持ちって言ってなかったっけ？
Never had
やったことがない
Of course 2002 was only slightly better
もちろん 2002 年の方がわずかに良かっただけです
So in 2003
それで2003年に
you are unlikely to be a ruling party
あなたは与党になる可能性が低い
just mentioned
先ほど述べた
According to this good economic performance
この好景気を受けて
you have to vote for me
あなたは私に投票しなければなりません
Actually for him
実は彼にとって
shift to the positive side of identification
アイデンティティのポジティブな側面にシフトする
There is also his motherhood quotes exist
彼の母性に関する名言もあります
Of course there are risky leads
もちろん、危険な憶測もあります。
Bian is a person willing to take risks
アー・ビアンはリスクをいとわない人だ
And he risked it
そして彼はそれを危険にさらした
There is this energy that is really mobilized by him
彼によって実際に動員されているエネルギーがあります
I will actually have an impact on SARS in 2003
実際に2003年にSARSに影響を与えることになる
I think we kinda understudied him
私たちは彼のことを少し勉強していなかったように思います
Because of this thing in that paragraph
その段落にあるこのことのせいで
The emotional impact on everyone is too great
全員への精神的影響が大きすぎる
is very very
とてもとても
Because it's a matter of life for everyone
それは誰にとっても命の問題だから
So if this thing
それで、もしこれが
able to talk about serious issues
深刻な問題について話すことができる
link together
一緒にリンクする
He has a lot of mobilizing energy
彼は多くの動員エネルギーを持っている
Anyway, that's what I meant to say
とにかく、それが言いたかったことです
Why did Ah Bian take this
なぜ阿ビアンはこれを受け取ったのか
Because he wants to be under the situation that the economy is not easy to mobilize
経済を動かしにくい状況にありたいから
to try to mobilize another piece
別の部分を動員しようとする
And after mobilizing this piece
そしてこの作品を動員した後、
In fact, it has the effect of his weakness
実際、それは彼の弱さの影響を及ぼします
The person who Virus has risk taking is related again
ウイルスがリスクを負っている人はまた関係します
But my big structure
でも私の大きな構造は
Although there is no way to explain
説明のしようもありませんが、
individual behavior
個人の行動
can explain
説明できる
If you mobilize mobilize mobilize mobilize to find
動員するなら動員する動員する
When the energy cannot be mobilized
エネルギーを動員できないとき
you will be forced to change
あなたは変化を余儀なくされるでしょう
So it has that big predictability
それほど大きな予測可能性があるのです
But some small ones don't know
でも小さな子たちは知らない人もいる
its all trial and error
すべて試行錯誤です
Then the second one you just mentioned
それから、先ほどおっしゃった 2 つ目です。
I think
私が思うに
Which direction do I go?
どの方向に行けばいいですか？
i think chris crossing
クリス・クロッシングだと思う
yes there is a certain possibility of it
はい、その可能性は確かにあります
but like i said
しかし、私が言ったように
Its external environment is the economy
その外部環境は経済です
so that thing
それでそのこと
if under its shadow
その影の下なら
will indeed have its influence
確かに影響力を持つだろう
But there is one more thing to note
しかし、もう一つ注意すべき点があります
when i talk about axis shift
軸シフトについて話すとき
There are economic factors
経済的要因もある
factors that identify with mobilization
動員と一致する要因
There is also the factor of cross-strait relations in the middle
中間には海峡両岸関係の要素もある
But this discourse in the middle
しかし、途中のこの会話
In fact, it is very instrumental
実際、それは非常に有益です
it means to say
それは言うことを意味します
economy is important
経済は重要です
not so much recognition
あまり認知されていない
For the good of the economy
経済のために
We must improve cross-strait relations
我々は両岸関係を改善しなければならない
so don't make too much recognition
だからあまり認識しないでください
If cross-strait relations are on schedule
両岸関係が予定通りであれば
Our economy is still in shambles
私たちの経済は依然として混乱状態にあります
that middle tool twist strap
真ん中のツールツイストストラップ
easily torn
簡単に破れます
once it's ripped
一度破れたら
you don't have to say
言う必要はありません
to do a good job in the economy
経済を良くするために
So we have to follow the other side
だから私たちは反対側に従わなければなりません
Let's talk about the 1992 Consensus or what?
1992 年コンセンサスか何かについて話しましょう。
not at all
全くない
If this becomes a common thought of many people
これが多くの人の共通の思いになれば
That also refers to the axis rotation we just talked about
これは、先ほど話した軸の回転にも関係します。
so
それで
hello teacher two
こんにちは、先生２
I just want to ask a question
ただ質問したいのですが
Then we talked so much about the transformation of the axis of political competition in Taiwan
それから私たちは台湾における政治的競争軸の変化についてたくさん話し合いました
So if Beijing as a foreigner
では、北京が外国人だったら
he came to talk
彼は話をしに来た
So Taiwan is now undergoing a transition from political competition to economic recognition
つまり台湾は現在、政治的競争から経済的承認への移行期にあるということだ
Then he personally said that he wanted to see this kind of criminal transfer
それから彼は個人的に、この種の刑事移送を見たいと言いました
I still hope that it will be more beneficial to face him on the ideological battlefield of the original two-party competition
私は、元の二大政党間の競争というイデオロギーの戦場で彼と対決することがより有益であることを今でも望んでいる。
Because in fact, Beijing, on the one hand, for example, we have him and ACFA
なぜなら、実際、北京には、例えば、彼とACFAがいるからです。
He has Fumao to infiltrate Taiwan's economy
福毛を台湾経済に浸透させている
He came to reinforce what the teacher said you brought
彼は先生があなたが持ってきたと言ったことを補強するために来ました
But recently there was an article in Beijing that said
しかし、最近北京で次のような記事がありました。
He thinks that the KMT has sunk me down
彼は国民党が私を沈めたと思っている
He thinks he said that the Kuomintang has begun to withdraw from the field of ideology
彼は国民党がイデオロギーの分野から撤退し始めていると言ったと思う
Don't talk about the unification of China or the unification of the two sides of the Taiwan Strait
中国の統一や台湾海峡の両側の統一について話してはいけない
So he actually has a little anxiety in his heart
だから彼は実は心の中に少し不安を抱えている
So the teacher's point of view is that
そこで先生の見解は、
In the end, this kind of typical profession is for Beijing
結局のところ、この種の典型的な職業は北京のものだ
What would he prefer to see
彼は何を見たがりますか
Thanks
ありがとう
I think what Beijing wants to see is
私が思うに北京が見たいのは
Everyone knows that Taiwan's economy
台湾経済は誰もが知っています
Mainland China's goodwill towards Taiwan can boost Taiwan's economy
中国本土の台湾に対する好意は台湾経済を押し上げる可能性がある
The focus is not on Taiwan's economic growth
焦点は台湾の経済成長ではない
Everyone can feel that cross-strait relations have a great impact on Taiwan's economy.
海峡両岸関係が台湾経済に大きな影響を与えていることは誰もが感じていることだろう。
is so important
とても重要です
In this way, the people of Taiwan will
このようにして、台湾の人々は、
while maintaining the existing framework
既存の枠組みを維持しながら
Even going one step further with mainland China
中国本土との関係も一歩前進
I think the police should think like this
警察もこう考えるべきだと思う
But he must have thought it wasn't enough
でも彼はそれだけでは足りないと思ったに違いない
He must be thinking about consciousness
彼は意識について考えているに違いない
can have further links
さらにリンクできる
I think the decision makers in Beijing
北京の意思決定者たちはこう思う
I talked to many scholars in the mainland
私は本土の多くの学者と話しました
they also talked
彼らも話しました
They feel as though economically
彼らは経済的に余裕があるように感じます
Let the mainland's point of view
本土の視点に立ってみましょう
seems to be economically
経済的に余裕があるようです
Also good for Taiwan
台湾にとっても良いことだ
Useless
使い物にならない
give him a lot of benefits
彼にたくさんの恩恵を与えてください
unnamed example
名前のない例
The swabfish from Xuejia
雪佳のスワブフィッシュ
As a result, has there been any change in the voting orientation of Xuejia?
その結果、Xuejia氏の投票の方向性に変化はありましたか？
no it's still green
いや、まだ緑だよ
So vote your money for the DPP
だから民進党にあなたのお金を投票してください
is this
これは
so he was thinking
それで彼は考えていた
Is there something deeper that matters more
もっと重要なことはありますか
he will feel
彼は感じるだろう
culture matters
文化の問題
So he will want to evoke in Taiwan
だから彼は台湾で呼び起こしたいと思うだろう
The kind in the earlier period
前期の種類
The one about Chinese culture
中国文化に関するもの
the sense of belonging, the sense of nostalgia
帰属意識、懐かしさ
And he often bullies
そして彼はよくいじめます
I already feel that we used to engage in the Cultural Revolution
すでに文化大革命をしていたような気がします
you say we're doing it wrong
あなたは私たちが正しくやっていないと言う
now our sister
今私たちの妹
The same college makes it all over the place
同じ大学があちこちでそれをやっている
we didn't get it right
私たちは正しく理解できませんでした
seems less interested
あまり興味がないようです
Actually, I think his voice
実際、彼の声だと思う
I mean we're a lot like you
つまり、私たちはあなたによく似ています
like the recent one
最近のもののように
The mainland wants the basic textbook of Chinese culture
大陸は中国文化の基礎教科書を望んでいる
In fact, I want to refer to some of Taiwan's
実際、台湾のいくつかについて言及したいと思います。
This also became their student
これも彼らの生徒になりました
his feeling is
彼の気持ちは
Ah, this is Chinese
ああ、これは中国語です
Is this what you're thinking of?
これはあなたが考えていることですか？
why divide
なぜ分けるのか
but what
でも何
something like this
このようなもの
so he will feel
そうすれば彼は感じるだろう
It is also important culturally
文化的にも重要です
He for the KMT
彼は国民党の支持者だ
that quit that battlefield
その戦場を去ったのは
feel very disapproving
非常に不満を感じる
There used to be a famous
昔有名なやつがありました
The head of the think tank is Zheng Bijian
シンクタンクの所長は鄭碧堅氏
He once led the mainland
彼はかつて本土を率いていた
A group of scholars went to Taiwan to talk with these scholars in Taiwan
学者グループが台湾に行き、台湾の学者たちと話をしました
Many of these scholars are blue
これらの学者の多くは青色です
Then these scholars also arranged to find one
そこで学者たちはまた、それを見つけるよう手配しました。
Everyone knows our good friend Chen Yindong
誰もが私たちの良き友人であるチェン・インドンを知っています
He is from Lu, right?
彼は魯出身ですよね？
Then served in this MAC
その後、この MAC で提供されます
Then he got up and read a passage
それから彼は立ち上がって一節を読みました
Then say hello, my opinion is actually different from yours
それからこんにちは、私の意見は実際にはあなたの意見とは異なります
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
Anyway, I expected this sound to be there
とにかく、この音があることを期待していました
What he can't understand the most is Ma Ying-jeou
彼が一番理解できないのは馬英九だ
Why are there such a group of people around?
なぜそのような人々が周りに集まっているのでしょうか？
Talk like the Democrats
民主党のように話す
this is what he thinks
これが彼が考えていることです
So he thinks it is possible to strengthen the culture
だから彼は文化を強化することが可能だと考えている
And then very worried about Taiwan's change of use
そして、台湾の用途変更を非常に心配しています
And then on the other hand
そしてその一方で
before that happened
それが起こる前に
Economically, we should try our best to keep Taiwan in check.
経済的には台湾を牽制するために全力を尽くすべきだ。
That's not Beijing's grand strategy, is it?
それは中国政府の大戦略ではないですよね？
Excuse me
すみません
left and right Kuomintang and Democratic Progressive Party
左右の国民党と民進党
future words may be said
未来の言葉が言われるかもしれない
left and right
左右
Each party has its own ideas
各党にはそれぞれの考えがある
not that i'm specifically left or right
私が特に左か右かというわけではありません
or
また
Like the KMT, their logic concept is derived from
国民党と同様に、彼らの論理概念は以下から派生しています。
The economy is not good because the cross-strait relations are not good
経済が良くないのは両岸関係が良くないからです
If cross-strait relations are not good
両岸関係が良好でない場合
I want to promote it, that is to move closer to China
それを推進したい、つまり中国に近づくことです
So he keeps saying that economy and identity are correlated
だから彼は経済とアイデンティティには相関関係があると言い続けている
So it is the emergence of the 1992 Consensus
1992年コンセンサスの登場です
That's like saying vitamins have ABC's
それはビタミンにはABCがあると言っているようなものです
But you say A is a vitamin and nothing else
でもあなたは、Aはビタミンであり、それ以外の何ものでもないと言っています
in that case would you feel this
その場合、あなたはそう感じますか
This logical concept is a bit strange
この論理概念は少し奇妙です
Then there is the 1992 Consensus
それから1992年のコンセンサスです。
That is, China and Taiwan are singing separately
つまり中国と台湾は別々に歌っているということだ
In fact there is an international
実はインターナショナルもあるんです
Then do you think it's just a kid arguing over there?
じゃあ、あそこで喧嘩しているのはただの子供だと思いますか？
just feel
ただ感じてください
very unreasonable
非常に不合理な
Then there was the KMT who suppressed trade unions before
それから、以前に労働組合を弾圧した国民党がありました。
But they don't raise money, do they?
でも彼らは資金を集めないんですよね？
Because they can get those properties from the moment they come
最初からそれらのプロパティを取得できるため、
Then he doesn't need any union support.
そうすれば彼は労働組合の支援を必要としなくなる。
that's it
それでおしまい
Yes, the KMT does not need the support of the trade unions
はい、国民党は労働組合の支援を必要としません
So he is not a leftist party
だから彼は左翼政党ではない
then you just said
それからあなたは今言いました
Is this an international look at these two kids fighting?
これはこの二人の子供が戦っている国際的な視点でしょうか？
You can also say yes
「はい」とも言えます
Not as if we see the Scots he wants independence from England
まるでスコットランド人がイングランドからの独立を望んでいるようには見えない
we probably don't feel anything
私たちはおそらく何も感じていない
ok the scots have a lot of feeling
わかりました、スコットランド人はたくさんの感情を持っています
Because the Scots have a lot of feeling
スコットランド人は感情が豊かだから
how we look
私たちがどのように見えるか
But if you watch some movies, you might feel something
でも映画を見たら何か感じるかもしれない
good
良い
But don't fight about matters of international concern
ただし、国際的な関心事については争わないでください
I remember I used to go to Singapore to take a taxi
よくシンガポールにタクシーに乗って行ったのを覚えています
that time happened to be
たまたまその時があった
At that time, it was not the era of Chen Shuipi, it was the era of Lee Teng-hui
当時は陳水妃の時代ではなく、李登輝の時代だった。
He immediately rebuked
彼はすぐに叱責した
Because of you, what are the Taiwanese doing?
あなたのせいで台湾人は何をしているのですか？
why is he so nervous
なぜ彼はそんなに緊張しているのですか
I also want to be so fierce.
私もそこまで激しくなりたいです。
He said that we are going to give the stock a big drop today
彼は、今日は株価を大幅に下げるつもりだと言いました
it means you get nervous
緊張するという意味です
war may follow
戦争が続くかもしれない
Because of the war, the economy of the entire region will be affected
戦争があるので地域全体の経済に影響が出るといわれています
will suffer this loss
この損失を被ることになる
So what everyone thinks is you don't fight
だからみんなが思ってるのは、あなたは戦わないってこと
So the international thinking is actually like this
国際的な考え方は実際には次のようなものです
But there is also constant international hope
しかし、国際的には絶え間ない希望もある
Taiwan and China are getting closer
台湾は中国本土に近づいている
Because they are afraid of China's rise
中国の台頭が怖いから
Then you think that if Taiwan and China are combined together
では、台湾と中国が一緒になったらと思います。
They are big wars
それらは大きな戦争だ
then i recognized them
それから私は彼らを認識しました
I say yes
はいと言います
you don't want us together
あなたは私たちと一緒にいたくないのですか
put them on
それらを着てください
But he's right
でも彼は正しい
just say you're right
ただあなたが正しいと言ってください
just get too close and i'm in danger
近づきすぎると危険です
real
本物
What do you say
あなたは何を言っていますか
What are you willing to give to Taiwan?
台湾に何をあげたいですか？
Let Taiwan not be so demanding of mainland China
台湾は中国本土に対してあまり要求しないようにしましょう
Then you have to sell five thousand Taiwan
そうすると台湾を5000売らなければなりません
would you like
よろしいですか
Are you scolding Beijing for being unhappy with promoting relations with Taiwan?
台湾との関係促進に不満を持っている中国政府を叱っているのでしょうか？
He said he wanted to maintain a good relationship with such a big
彼は、このような大企業と良好な関係を維持したいと述べた
For this he sacrificed Taiwan
そのために台湾を犠牲にした
And when Taiwan I want to develop some relations with the mainland
そして台湾が本土との関係を発展させたいとき
He has started to blame Taiwan
彼は台湾を非難し始めた
But he can't give Taiwan any benefit
しかし台湾に何の利益も与えられない
so that
となることによって
Internationally, it is actually very realistic.
国際的に見て、それは非常に現実的です。
don't fight
戦わないでください
then you stop
それならやめてください
your current situation
あなたの現在の状況
Then
それから
don't get too close to him
彼に近づきすぎないでください
Because I am a little afraid of the big China
大きな中国はちょっと怖いから
Anyway, everything I think about you
とにかく、私があなたについて考えているすべてのこと
Anyway, starting from my own strength
とにかく自分の力から
basically like this
基本的にこのように
you go ahead and have a problem
問題が発生しました
Sorry because there seem to be four or five questions
質問が4、5あるようなのでごめんなさい
That is the Kuomintang and the Democratic Progressive Party
それが国民党と民進党です
They each said not to rush away
彼らはそれぞれ、急いで逃げないようにと言いました
become leftist or rightist
左翼か右翼になる
is to become leftists and rightists
左翼と右翼になることだ
knowledge all together
知識をすべて一緒に
It’s just a party, it has leftist ideas and rightist ideas
それはただの政党であり、左派の考えも右派の考えもある
Co-exist
共同存在
not easy
簡単ではありません
Because these two are not in the party
この二人はパーティにいないので
It is usually said that we engage in luxury tax
一般的に贅沢税をやっていると言われます
Its rightists always have to oppose it
その右派は常にそれに反対しなければならない
I don't know the reason for these rightists
右翼の理由が分からない
Maybe it's because of the overlap of ideology
イデオロギーが重なるからかもしれない
Or
また
What about the people in the air-conditioned house you drank
あなたが飲んだエアコンの効いた家の人々はどうですか？
it is broken disapproval
それは壊れた不承認です
it will have friction on various interests
さまざまな利害関係で摩擦が生じるだろう
Can such a situation exist in the same party?
同じパーティ内にそのような状況が存在し得るでしょうか?
Unless your party happens to be just below the middle level
たまたまあなたのパーティーが中レベルより少し下でない限り
The distance between your left and right is actually not very far from each other
あなたの左と右の距離は実際にはそれほど遠くない
that would be possible
それは可能だろう
but my opinion is
しかし私の意見は
if the economy is bad
景気が悪いと
It means that the economic endowment becomes smaller
経済的余裕が少なくなるということです
When the economic endowment becomes smaller
経済的余力が少なくなったとき
share that talent
その才能を分かち合う
The truth and the conflict become bigger
真実と葛藤は大きくなる
The left and right cutting methods are different
左右でカット方法が異なります
very difficult
非常に難しい
I want this party to split into two parties
この党を二党に分裂させたい
What is needed is that the party has a relatively large force
必要なのは、党が比較的大きな勢力を持つことである
eat that little power
そのわずかな力を食べる
then take it aside
それからそれを脇に置いてください
it's more likely
その可能性が高いです
Because I haven't seen in any example
例を見たことがないので
Horizontal left and horizontal right will appear in the middle of a party
パーティの途中に横左と横右が出現します
I'm afraid it's not easy
残念ですが、それは簡単ではありません
Because it still has to maintain a party
まだパーティを維持しなければならないから
still have a question
まだ質問があります
good
良い
Hello Mr. Wu
こんにちは、ウーさん
In fact, the problem is a bit similar to the one just now.
実際、この問題は今の問題と少し似ています。
And I'm curious too
そして、私も興味があります
Did you just mention that there are two axes?
2つの軸があると先ほど言いましたか？
We all know this axis.
この軸は誰もが知っています。
but as a scholar
しかし学者として
I don't know if you went
あなたが行ったかどうか知りません
some thoughts
いくつかの考え
That’s how we get to the major economy file
これが主要な経済ファイルに到達する方法です
because it sounds like
のように聞こえるので
we can probably accept saying
おそらく私たちはこう言うことを受け入れることができるでしょう
economy is an important issue
経済は重要な問題です
but you are the last
でもあなたが最後です
You said something in your tappa game
タッパゲームで何か言いましたね
We use left and right to divide
左と右を使って分割します
In fact, we don't go left and right.
実際、私たちは右にも左にも行きません。
Alignment with our political party or political competition
政党または政治的競争との連携
It sounds like we are currently or the economy is on this line
現在、経済はこの線上にあるように思えます
Much depends on our economic relationship with China
多くは中国との経済関係に依存します
Including your example of using the EC method is also taking such an example
EC手法を使った例も含めて、このような例も取り上げています
so i was wondering if you had some ideas
それで、何かアイデアがあるかどうか疑問に思っていました
That is to say, in the case of economics, the face-to-face inquiry is actually
つまり、経済学の場合、対面での調査は実際には
Maybe it's not about the competition
もしかしたら競争の話ではないかもしれない
but one that is highly associated with identity
しかしそれはアイデンティティに深く関係している
Or a direction unrelated to identity
あるいはアイデンティティとは無関係な方向
Thanks
ありがとう
If we say that the economic route is the same as the recognized route
経済ルートと認められたルートが同じだと言うなら
it should have been mainland words
それは本土の言葉であるべきだった
of course something went wrong
もちろん何か問題が発生しました
Because I think a question asked by emerging TTS
新興TTSからの質問だと思うので
it only has one
それは1つだけです
That is, it wants to ask you about the economy
つまり、経済について聞きたいのです
Do you think the government should
政府はそうすべきだと思いますか
it has a
それは
its problem
その問題
Um
えーっと
it will
そうなる
Advocating that the government should promote social welfare economically is to use ten to express
政府が社会福祉を経済的に促進すべきであると主張することは、10 を使って表現することである
Excuse me, are you closer?
すみません、近くですか？
on this subject
この教科では
I think Wu Minnie is here
ウー・ミニーがここにいると思う
As far as Wu Minxi is concerned
ウー・ミンシーに関する限り
Her lecture seat is very suitable
彼女の講義の席はとても適している
so she should make a
だから彼女は作るべきだ
One is social welfare in Hong Kong
一つは香港の社会福祉です
One is very appropriate
1つは非常に適切です
We probably only have this problem
おそらくこの問題だけが問題です
In addition, other topics are not distinguished
また、他のトピックは区別されません
So basically you can use this question
したがって、基本的にこの質問を使用できます
come get your
取りに来てください
Mark the left and right items
左右の項目にマークを付けます
0 to 10?
0から10まで？
On the other side, this cultural machine has
一方で、この文化機構は、
So it can be used like this
したがって、このように使用できます
special representation of this space
この空間の特別な表現
like that
そのように
is the 2011 president of the American Political Science Association.
2011 年アメリカ政治学会会長。
at his presidential address
彼の大統領演説で
specifically mentioned this
これについて特に言及しました
The axis they thought was still just right
彼らが思った軸はまだちょうどいい
7 minutes left and right
左右7分
But he has now switched to speaking from your point of view
しかし彼は今、あなたの視点から話すようになりました
and like this
そしてこのように
It turned out that he came out with a social conservatism
彼は社会保守主義をカミングアウトしたことが判明した
Then his horizontal axis is the household income
横軸は世帯収入です
he is not around
彼は近くにいません
he is household income
彼は世帯収入です
The horizontal axis is more interesting
横軸のほうが面白い
how often does he go to church
彼はどのくらいの頻度で教会に行きますか
This is to show your conservatism and your profit
これはあなたの保守主義と利益を示すためです
Then he found out that household income if so
それから彼は、世帯収入があれば、それを調べました。
words from your point of view
あなたの視点からの言葉
is so
そうだね
Is that right?
そうですか？
Then the higher you go, the more conservative you are
そして上に行けば行くほど保守的になる
The lower you go, the more liberal you are
下に行けば行くほど、よりリベラルになります
The farther to this side, the lower the income
こちら側に行くほど収入が低くなります
The more you go to this side, the higher your income
こちら側に行けば行くほど収入が高くなります
so the democrats are here
だから民主党はここにいる
And the Republican Party is here
そして共和党もここにある
His axis is cut like this
彼の軸はこのようにカットされています
so you don't ask me what i mean
だから、私が何を言いたいのかは聞かないでください
So it is possible to use something like
したがって、次のようなものを使用することができます
Senior Wu
呉先輩
In education or in Wu Xuechang
教育でも呉雪昌でも
please teach me
教えて下さい
Between identity and economy are two different gates
アイデンティティと経済の間には 2 つの異なる門がある
Looks like it's depoliticized
非政治化されているように見える
There are still some deficiencies
まだいくつかの欠陥があります
Just a continuation of his previous question
彼の前の質問の続きです
Economy is still a main axis Life
やはり経済が主軸 生活
actually agreeing here
実際にここで同意します
it's just that we separate it
それを分けているだけです
for two opposites
正反対の二人にとって
So called separate
いわゆるセパレート
You can use the opposition between the upper class and the lower class
上位階級と下位階級の間の対立を利用することができます
or we use the opposite of identity
またはアイデンティティの反対を使用します
just a matter of sampling
サンプリングの問題だけ
practical economic problems
実際的な経済問題
We can see from the trend of the world
世界の動向からわかる
American welfare
アメリカの福祉
then go to democracy
それなら民主主義に行きなさい
This slowly walks inside a dead activity
これは死んだアクティビティの中をゆっくりと歩きます
it's already the world is flat
もう世界は平らだ
it has no advantage
それは何のメリットもありません
Then oil, war, weapons, stuff like that
それから石油、戦争、兵器、そのようなもの
In fact it has no advantage
実際には何のメリットもない
but currently it looks like
しかし、現在は次のようです
China Korea and Singapore
中国、韓国、シンガポール
It is the dominant power of the whole country
それは国全体の支配力です
On the contrary, compared with this democratic progressive way
それどころか、この民主主義的な進歩的なやり方と比較すると、
Productivity is more efficient
生産性がより効率的になる
so these few
それで、これらのいくつかの
So from this point of view, for example, the two opposites of democracy
したがって、この観点から、たとえば、民主主義の 2 つの相反するもの
The two opposing identities of Taiwan
台湾における二つの相反するアイデンティティ
In fact, there are two hands behind
実際、後ろには2つの手があります
One is the hands of the CCP and the hands of the United States
一つは中国共産党の手、もう一つは米国の手です。
Because in the early years we got our economy from the United States
なぜなら、初期の頃、私たちは米国から経済を得たからです。
Benefit Oyen got a lot of orders
利益 Oyen は多くの注文を獲得しました
Like which side of China is the same?
中国のどちら側が同じですか？
It will give us quite a lot of benefits
それは私たちに非常に多くの利益をもたらします
So it's also called what counts for us
だからそれは私たちにとって何が重要なのかとも呼ばれます
What's the benefit?
メリットは何ですか?
It is also to give us some favor
それは私たちに何かを与えるためでもあります
so wrestling in the back
だから後ろで格闘してる
It's because of the shadow behind that hand
その手の影のせいで
The CCP and the United States are actually behind the hand
中国共産党と米国は実際には背後にいる
behind two parties
2つのパーティーの後ろに
still have this hand in it
まだこの手を持っている
Interfering with Taiwan operations between us
私たちの台湾での活動を妨害する
So Taiwan is a
それで台湾は、
under the big gear
大きなギアの下で
middle pinion
ミドルピニオン
So when it comes to Taiwan's identity and economy
台湾のアイデンティティと経済に関して言えば、
Recognition is just a marketing position
認知度は単なるマーケティング上の地位にすぎない
That is to say, to position you and go there
つまり、自分の位置を決めてそこに行くということです
there must be opposition
反対があるはずだ
This factor actually depends on some other
この要素は実際には他の要素に依存します
Does factor come in to see politics more?
もっと政治を見る要素が入ってくるのでしょうか？
Taiwan's trend will be clearer
台湾の動向がより鮮明になる
I agree with this thing
私はこのことに同意します
Originally it was an emotional attachment
もともとは感情的な愛着だった
economy is important
経済は重要です
not just think about it
ただ考えるだけではなく
It is also an emotional attachment to the economy
それは経済に対する感情的な愛着でもあります
but you can say
しかし、あなたは言うことができます
not like that
あのようでなく
real life needs
現実の生活のニーズ
doomed in gestalt
ゲシュタルトに陥る運命にある
but real life
しかし現実の生活
whatever is good
何でも良い
how totally unacceptable
まったく受け入れられないこと
I heard that I am happy not to be in charge
担当じゃなくてよかったと聞いた
that is
あれは
its living income
その生活収入
Morality may be quite low
口德可能蠻低
but its expectations may not be high
しかし、その期待は高くないかもしれません
So many people are full of the psychological aspect
精神的な面でいっぱいの人が多すぎる
Then you just mentioned that
それからあなたは今それを言いました
Identity is more illusory
アイデンティティはより幻想的になる
Then the economy is a more practical thing
そうすれば経済はより現実的なものになる
i agree
同意します
these two things
この2つのこと
in particular
特に
not so strong identity distinction
それほど強いアイデンティティの区別ではない
When comparing with economic
経済的に比較すると
possible economic
可能性のある経済的
overwhelm this recognition
この認識を覆す
I think Taiwan
台湾だと思う
It's kind of like this situation
なんだかこんな状況です
Many of the countries mentioned are like Dongdong
言及された国の多くは東東に似ています
many places
多くの場所
But I really can't see it at all
でも本当に全然見えない
a bit of economic logic there
そこには経済論理が少し含まれています
It's that different race
それは違う人種です
between different village schools
異なる村の学校の間で
deep hatred
深い憎しみ
So it got to the point where
それで、それは次の点に達しました
it's really hard to draw
描くのは本当に難しいです
Even if the north shore is the same as the south
北岸と南岸が同じだとしても
So I think it might depend on the place
なので、場所にもよると思いますが、
But there is no such thing in Taipei anymore
しかし、台北にはもうそのようなものはありません
you just said
あなたは今言いました
Is there a hand outside?
外に手はありますか？
of course
もちろん
Then it manipulates
それからそれは操作します
of course we manipulate
もちろん操作します
but manipulator
しかしマニピュレーター
nor can it decide
それも決められない
what will the ending be
結末はどうなるのか
Let me give another example
別の例を挙げてみましょう
You see the United States is so powerful
米国が非常に強力であることがわかります
The overlord of the world ran to fight
世界の覇者は戦いに走った
It's the sinful Afghanistan.
罪深いアフガニスタンだ。
13 years of fighting
13年間の戦い
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
Right, how about it? It will push the Tulian to withdraw its troops. It may not be possible to deal with him.
そう、どうですか? トゥーリエン軍を撤退に追い込むことになるでしょう。彼に対処するのは不可能かもしれません。
What do you say about the physical, cultural, military, and political power that you want to stop?
あなたはこれを物質的、文化的、軍事的、政治的な力だと言います
Guardianship of the poorest circle
最も貧しいサークルの後見人
He has nothing to do with him
彼とは何の関係もありません
So the power of diplomacy is to influence Taiwan
つまり外交の力で台湾に影響を与えることができる
But the way he influences results
しかし、彼が結果に影響を与える方法
It may also be beyond the power of diplomacy to conceive
それは外交の力では想像できない可能性もある
Another point is that no one likes to be manipulated.
もう一つのポイントは、誰も操作されることを好まないということです。
So if you take us to the crossbar, who is very clearly manipulating us?
それでは、私たちをクロスバーに連れて行った場合、誰が私たちを操作しているのは明らかでしょうか?
he may have a distaste will come out
彼は嫌悪感を持っているかもしれない
Because antipathy could also turn into an election
反感が選挙に発展する可能性もあるから
a very important factor
非常に重要な要素
What you said is what I agree with, on a large scale
あなたが言ったことは、大規模な点で私も同意します
But when the actual sexual desire has an impact, it depends on the situation.
ただし、実際の性欲が影響するかどうかは状況によって異なります。
What impact will it have when
いつどんな影響が出るのか
He knew it very well Zhu Wenqing
彼はそれをよく知っていた 朱文青
once before the taiwan election
台湾の選挙の前に一度
I'll let you guys feel that you can't do anything wrong.
何も悪いことはできないと感じてもらいましょう。
As a result, after you talked about this
その結果、この話をした後、
Elections in Taiwan
台湾の選挙
The child did not achieve what he wanted
子供は望んでいたものを達成できなかった
so
それで
Hello, teacher
こんにちは先生
Excuse me, just ask
すみません、ちょっと聞いてください
In the process of transaction reform
取引改革の真っ最中
There are so-called multi-entry water and multiple copies in one tank
いわゆるマルチエントリーの水が1つのタンクに複数あります
Is that a multi-cylinder?
それは多気筒ですか？
It is this history and luck
これが歴史と幸運です
A prohibition on the question of identity
アイデンティティに関する質問の禁止
That is to say
つまり
When the Democrats were in power
民主党が政権を握っていた頃
This syllabus is
このシラバスは、
bully sinicization
いじめっ子の中国化
When the Democratic Party was in power
民主党政権のとき
It's just bullying Taiwan
それは台湾をいじめているだけだ
If you are a general recruit of a course
コースの一般採用の場合
History or Chinese Yunhua
歴史とか中国の雲華とか
General tricks in Chinese English
中国語英語の一般的なトリック
or a trade worker
または貿易労働者
then you should be
それならあなたはそうあるべきです
how to take responsibility
責任の取り方
Or just pay attention when students take exams
あるいは、学生が試験を受けるときにだけ注意してください
How much Gao Wen can take an exam?
Gao Wen はどれくらいの試験を受けることができますか?
Can go to star high school or star university
スター高校やスター大学に進学できる
You will pay more attention to that impression
その印象にもっと注目するでしょう
then you will have a hard time answering
そうなると答えるのに苦労するだろう
because you are a teacher
あなたは教師だから
this is no way
これはありえない
His syllabus determines
彼のシラバスが決定する
Textbook decided
教科書決定
Then the exam is like that
じゃあ試験もそんな感じだよ
Of course you let your students
もちろん生徒たちにやらせます
able to do well
うまくやれる
So in that situation
それで、その状況では
how to get him out
彼を追い出す方法
The standard answer that is considered correct
正しいと考えられる標準的な答え
you can't say easily
簡単には言えないよ
The classmate's current textbook has changed
クラスメートの現在の教科書が変わりました
but the current direction
しかし、現在の方向性
so you make us
だからあなたが私たちを作るのです
For this reason
このために
considered wrong
間違っていると考えられる
We still have to choose D
まだDを選ばなければなりません
instead of choosing A
Aを選ぶ代わりに
it's hard
それは難しい
then you talk about that
それからあなたはそれについて話します
In the beginning this and that decision
はじめにあれこれの決断
What should be the curriculum
カリキュラムはどうあるべきか
that stuff is more difficult
そっちのほうが難しいよ
why is it difficult
なぜ難しいのか
because it's ingrained
それは染み付いているから
values ​​and beliefs
価値観と信念
see many historians
多くの歴史家に会う
The view of each other is south far north side
お互いの景色は南極北側
have heard their editorials on many occasions
彼らの論説を何度も聞いた
some people think
一部の人々は思う
Taiwan is a Chinese nation
台湾は中華民族です
like the one in this extension
この拡張機能のような
one this
これを一つ
how to say
どのように言って
one
一個
a river street
川の通り
a pioneering region
先駆的な地域
So here's the
それで、これが
all this
このすべて
This traditional Chinese culture
この伝統的な中国文化は、
then in this
それからこの中で
Under this special situation
この特殊な状況下で
Then this displayed
すると、これが表示されました
i really thought you understood
あなたは本当に理解していると思いました
Some people don't see it that way at all
全然そんな風に見てない人もいるよ
Then he imagined himself
それから彼は自分自身を想像しました
Follow the influence from mainland China
中国本土からの影響をたどる
or something
か何か
is highly repulsive
反発力が高い
because how do you go
だってどうやって行くの
I got it
わかった
Actually now
実は今
what actually happened
実際に何が起こったのか
The Democratic Progressive Party will say that scholars who have a little more access to the road will go in
民進党はもう少し道路にアクセスできる学者が入ると言うだろう
The KMT will try to squeeze more scholars into it
国民党はさらに多くの学者を党に押し込もうとするだろう
Some people are tighter
もっときつい人もいる
Some people are more skillful
もっと上手な人もいる
Some people are not strong enough
荷物が足りない人もいる
and how to get the final syllabus
最終的なシラバスの入手方法
A Political Compromise
一個Political Compromise
this is what actually happened
これが実際に起こったことです
It is actually reflected in Taiwan's own
それは実際に台湾自身にも反映されています
The confrontation of many values
多くの価値観の対立
Just like the stone hills in the mainland I just mentioned
先ほど言った本土の石の丘のように
stone hill
石の丘
Mathematics and Mathematics
数学と数学
talk about interests
要講利益
Each of these can tell something
それぞれが何かを伝えることができます
But it doesn't really matter there
でも、そこはあまり関係ないんです
when speaking
話すとき
Does it touch my heart
私の心に響きますか
As for whether it touches my heart
心に響くかどうかは
It depends on my growing environment
生育環境にもよるけど
background family etc.
背景家族など
are directly linked
直接リンクされている
i find it difficult
それは難しいと思います
this thing to comment
コメントするのはこれ
But the syllabus is set, the textbook is set
でもシラバスも教科書も決まっている
people who read the syllabus
シラバスを読んだ人たち
will have a certain opinion
一定の意見を持つだろう
this is yes
これはそうです
No wonder both sides want
双方が望んでいるのも不思議ではない
scramble so fast
とても早くスクランブルします
Dominance?
支配力？
OK
OK
we are only for a minute
私たちはあと少しです
So our young friend from earlier
それで、先ほどの若い友人
I'm asking for advice after the meeting
会議後にアドバイスを求めています
i said a few words before
前に少し言いました
Director Wu gave a very brilliant speech today
呉所長は今日とても素晴らしいスピーチをしました
But his answer is still on the ground
しかし、彼の答えはまだ地上にあります
It's just that political scientists are different from my historians.
ただ、政治学者は私の歴史家とは違うんです。
once i was at a dinner party
かつて私はディナーパーティーに出席していた
anxious to go home
家に帰るのが不安
Japan finds Tian University's vice president
日本が天大学の副学長を人事
say anything
何でも言って
what are you doing in such a hurry
そんなに急いで何をしているのですか
Will it still be common?
まだ一般的になるのでしょうか？
tends to be a nice guy
いい奴になる傾向がある
not later
後ではない
text is writing the same
テキストも同じことを書いています
But politics is different
でも政治は違う
Political science will not be the same the day after tomorrow
政治学は明後日も同じではない
Look at Director Wu's topic today
今日のウー監督のトピックを見てください
left for us
私たちのために残されました
Tomorrow and the day after tomorrow, the Democratic Progressive Party of the Jiangnan Kuomintang
明日と明後日は江南国民党民進党
what has become
何が起こったのか
Still uncustomized
まだカスタマイズされていない
still developing
まだ発展途上の
leave us with a question to think about
考えるべき質問を残してください
a thinking difficulty
思考の困難
Thank you for his wonderful speech today
今日は彼の素晴らしいスピーチをありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you.
ありがとう。